<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root> 

<misc>Misc
   <keyItem>
       <itemName consumableList="Blood_Dreg">Blood Dreg</itemName>
       <description>The Vilebloods of Cainhurst, blood-lusting hunters,
    see these frightful things in coldblood.
    
    They often appear in the blood of echo fiends, that is to say,
    the blood of hunters. Queen Annalise partakes in these blood
    dregs offerings, so that she may one day bear the Child of
    Blood, the next Vileblood heir. </description>
   </keyItem>
    
   <keyItem>
       <itemName keyItemList="Gold_Pendant">Gold Pendant</itemName>
       <description> Pendant of Vicar Amelia. 
    <use>Use to change into a Blood Gem,</use>
    which fortifies weapons.
    
    This pendant, passed down among the vicars who head the Healing Church,
    is a reminder of the cautionary adage. To reveal the adage,
    touch the altar skull. </description>
       </keyItem>
    
    
    
    
    <page n="78"></page>
    
    
    <toolItem> 
<itemName toolList="Hand_Lantern">Hand Lantern</itemName>
 Small portable lantern.
    
    <description>
    This hunting accessory provides light while leaving
    both hands free to hold weapons. The torch, however, provides a stronger source of light.
    </description>
    </toolItem>
    
    <toolItem>
<itemName toolList="Monocular">Monocular</itemName>
 Monocular used to View things up close.
    
   <description>
       Not a hunter's tool, but a simple antique, to be used as one sees fit.</description>
    </toolItem>
   
   <keyItem>
   <itemName keyItemList="Red_Jeweled_Brooch">Red Jeweled Brooch</itemName>
 A woman's bright-red brooch, engraved with the name Viola.
    
    <description>Perhaps the jewel is a gift from a hunter. <use>Use to change into
       a droplet blood gem that fortifies any weapon.</use>
    
    With the proper workshop tool, various weapons can be
    fortified.</description>
      </keyItem>
   
      <toolItem>
      <itemName toolList="Shining_Coins">Shining Coins</itemName>
 Various coins that are particularly luminous.
    
    <description> There are very few uses for spare change during the hunt,
    but these will serve as guides through the darkness.
    
    Or, one could save them until morning, if it ever comes.
    </description>
         </toolItem>
            
      <consuableItem>
         <itemName consumableList="Tear_Stone">Tear Stone</itemName>
  <description>Silver-shining tear stone.
    
   <use>Use to change into a droplet blood gem that fortifies any
      weapon.</use>
    
    A doll sheds neither blood nor tears, and thus its nature
    remains unknown. </description>
         </consuableItem>
   
         <toolItem>
         <itemName toolList="Tiny_Music_Box">Tiny Music Box</itemName>
 A small music box received from a young Yharnam girl.
    Plays a song shared by her mother and father.
    
    Inside the lid is a small scrap of paper, perhaps an old
    message. Two names can be made out, however faintly.
    
    Viola and Gascoigne.
    
            </toolItem>
    
    
    <page n="79"></page>
    
    
            <consumableItem>
            <itemName consumableList="Vermin">Vermin</itemName>
 
    <description>A centipede-like creature discovered on successful hunts by
    League hunters.
    
    Vermin, found hidden within filth, are only seen by League
    confederates, and are the root of man's impurity. The League
    has assumed the task of finding and crushing all vermin.
    
    Perhaps there is some mercy in the madness. Those who
    wish to see vermin can, and those who choose to are
    provided with boundless purpose. </description>
               </consumableItem>
    
               <consumableItem>
               <itemName consumableList="Coldblood">Coldblood</itemName>
                  </consumableItem>
   
                  <consumableItem>
                  <itemName consumableList="Coldblood_Dew">Coldblood Dew</itemName>
                  
 
    <description> Droplet of coldblood containing Blood Echoes.
    
        <use>Use to gain Blood Echoes.</use>
    
    Hunters sustained by the dream gain strength from Blood
    Echoes. They imbibe the blood with thoughts of reverence,
    indeed gratitude, for their victims.</description>
                     </consumableItem>
   
    <consumableItem>
         <itemName consumableList="Thick_Coldblood">Thick Coldblood</itemName>
        <description>A thick droplet of coldblood containing Blood Echoes.
    
    <use>Use to gain a larger amount of Blood Echoes.</use>
    
    A strong will produces thick blood. Doubtless, the product of
    obsession, a potent source of human strength.</description>
    </consumableItem>
   
   <consumableItem>
  <itemName consumableList="Frenzied_Coldblood">Frenzied Coldblood</itemName>
         <description>A rich droplet of coldblood containing Blood Echoes.
    
    <use>Use to gain frenzied Blood Echoes.</use>
    
    This manifestation of madness comes from a mind teetering
    on the very brink, but has a sane mind ever produced
    anything of true significance?</description>
   </consumableItem>
   
  <consumableItem>
     <itemName consumableList="Kin_Coldblood">Kin Coldblood</itemName>
      <description>Coldblood of inhuman kin of the cosmos, brethren of the
    Great Ones.
    
    <use>Use to gain unspeakable Blood Echoes.</use>
    
    
    <page n="80"></page>
    
    
    Dare not to delve into the world beyond humanity, the
    eldritch Truth touched upon long ago at Byrgenwerth.</description>
  </consumableItem>
   
        <consumableItem>
         <itemName consumableList="Great_One_Coldblood">Great One Coldblood</itemName>
      <description>Relic containing the Blood Echoes of a Great One.
    
    <use>Use to gain cosmically nightmarish Blood Echoes.</use>
    
    Like a true revelation, this uncanny relic defies</description>
    understanding.
        </consumableItem>
   
        <consumableItem>
    <itemName consumableList="Old_Great_One_Coldblood">Old Great One Coldblood</itemName>
 Relic containing the Blood Echoes of an Old Great One.
    
    <use>Use to gain cosmically nightmarish Blood Echoes.</use>
    
    Like a true revelation, this uncanny relic defies
    understanding.
        </consumableItem>
   
      <consumableItem>
   <itemName consumableList="Revered_Great_One_Coldblood*">Revered Great One Coldblood*</itemName>
     <description>Relic containing the blood echoes of a revered Great One.
    
    <use>Use to gain cosmically nightmarish Blood Echoes.</use>
    
    Like a true revelation, this uncanny relic defies
    understanding
    *Has not been found through normal means</description>
      </consumableItem>
</misc>

<arcaneBloodtingeTools>Arcane/Bloodtinge Tools
    
<spellItem>
   <itemName spellList="A_Call_Beyond">A Call Beyond</itemName>
 <description>One of the secrets of the Choir.
    
    Long ago, the Healing Church used phantasms to reach a
    lofty plane of darkness, but failed to make contact with the
    outer reaches of the cosmos.
    
    The rite failed to achieve its intended purpose, but instead
    created a small exploding star, now a powerful part of the
    Choir's arsenal.
    At times, failure is the mother of invention.</description>
</spellItem>
    <toolItem>
    <itemName toolList="Augur_of_Ebrietas">Augur of Ebrietas</itemName>
    <description>One of the secret rites of the Choir,
 high-ranking members of the Healing Church.
    
    
    <page n="81"></page>
    
    
    
    Use spirits, the invertebrates known to be augurs of
    the Great Ones, to partially summon abandoned Ebrietas.
    
    One of the few rites that allow one to directly utilize
    the power of the Great Ones, and evidence that
    the Choir had approached the eldritch Truth.</description>
    </toolItem>
   
   <spellItem>
<itemName spellList="Beast_Roar">Beast Roar</itemName>
<description>One of the forbidden hunter tools
    made by Irreverent Izzy.
    
    Borrow the strength of the terrible undead darkbeasts,
    if only for a moment, to blast surrounding foes back with
    the force of a roaring beast.
    
    The indescribable sound is broadcast with the caster's
    own vocal cords, which begs the question, what terrible
    things lurk deep within the frames of men?</description>
      </spellItem>
    
   
   <spellItem>
    <itemName spellList="Empty_Phantasm_Shell">Empty Phantasm Shell</itemName>
    <description>Empty invertebrate shell that is said to be a familiar of a
    Great One. The Healing Church has discovered a great
    variety of invertebrates, or phantasms, as they are called.
    
    Shells with slime still harbour arcane power, and can be
    rubbed on weapons to imbue them with their strength.</description>
   </spellItem>
   
      <spellItem>
<itemName spellList="Executioner's_Gloves">Executioner's Gloves</itemName>
<description>One of the secret treasures hidden in Cainhurst.
    The gloves of an executioner from a faraway land.
    
    Passed from executioner father to executioner son,
    these gloves can be used to summon wrathful spirits
    of the past by smearing them with blood.
    
    It is said that the nobles found in immeasurable delight
    in the dances of these vengeful specters.</description>
      </spellItem>
   
         <spellItem>
<itemName spellList="Choir_Bell">Choir Bell</itemName>
<description>Special hunter tool of the Choir, high-ranking
    member of the church. Fashioned after a bell that
    projects an arcane sound across planes of existence.
    
    
    
    
    <page n="82"></page>
    
    
    The sound of this smaller, silver version of the bell
    does not cross planes, but grants vigor and healing</description>
    to all cooperators.
         </spellItem>
    
            <spellItem>
<itemName spellList="Messenger’s_Gift">Messenger’s Gift</itemName>
<description>A strange gift from the messengers, inhabitants of
    the dream who revere the brave hunters.
    
    <use>Use to envelop oneself in a black nightmarish mist,
        then transform into a messenger. The illusion is a parlor
        trick, and any large movement will break the spell. 
    
    To preserve the guise, proceed very slowly.</use></description>
            </spellItem>
    
               <spellItem>
    <itemName spellList="Old_Hunter_Bone">Old Hunter Bone</itemName>

<description>The bone of an old hunter whose name is lost.
    
    It is said that he was an apprentice to old Gehrman, and a
    practitioner of the art of Quickening, a technique particular
    to the first hunters.
    
    It is most appropriate that hunters, carriers of the torch who
    are sustained by the dream, would tease an old art from his
    remains.</description>
               </spellItem>
    
                  <spellItem>
    <itemName spellList="Tiny_Tonitrus">Tiny Tonitrus</itemName>
    <description>Tonitrus is a unique weapon crafted by Archibald,
    the infamous eccentric of the Healing Church workshop.
    
    This is a similar morning star mace that utilizes
    Quicksilver Bullets. When struck into the ground,
    it recreates the blue sparks that are said to surround
    the darkbeasts.
    
    Like Archibald's masterpiece, this too
    is a superb conductor of the powerful blue sparks.</description>
                  </spellItem>
    
                     <spellItem>
    <itemName spellList="Accursed_Brew">Accursed Brew</itemName>
    <description>Skull of a local from the violated fishing village. The inside
    of the skull was forcibly searched for eyes, as evidenced by
    innumerable scratches and indentations.
    
    No wonder the skull became stewed in curses.
    
    
    <page n="83"></page>
    
    
    
    They who offer baneful chants.
    Weep with them, as one in trance.</description>
                     </spellItem>
                     
                        <spellItem>
    <itemName spellList="Blacksky_Eye">Blacksky Eye</itemName>
    <description>Soft eye blessed by a phantasm. They were
    discovered through Byrgenwerth's contact with the
    arcane, but in the end revealed nothing.
    
    Deep within the eye lies a vast stretch of dark
    sky that rumbles with an endless meteor storm.
    The slightest rub of the tiny orb, and the rock
    will tumble and soar.</description>
                        </spellItem>
    
                           <spellItem>
    <itemName spellList="Madara’s_Whistle">Madara’s Whistle</itemName>
    <description>Whistle of the Madaras twins, denizens of the Forbidden Woods.
    The twins grew up alongside a poisonous snake, and
    developed a silent, inhuman kinship.
    
    The poisonous snake grew uncontrollably, raised on a
    healthy diet of beast entrails. Even after their deaths, it is
    said to respond to the call of the twins' whistle from within the Nightmare.</description>
                              </spellItem>
</arcaneBloodtingeTools>

    </root>