<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<?xml-model href="../documentation/mainSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<lore>
<keyItem>
    

<itemName keyItemList="Cainhurts_Badge">Cainhurst Badge</itemName>
<description>Badge of the royal guards of Cainhurst, loyal guardians of
        the Vileblood Queen Annalise.

    The Vilebloods are hunters of blood, and hunt prey as they
        search for blood dregs. The hunter who joins them is faced with a decision to merely borrow their strength, or to
        become one of them, heart and soul.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Eye_Watcher_Badge">Cosmic Eye Watcher Badge</itemName>
<description>Badge of a member of the Choir, elites of the
        Healing Church.
        
        The eye signifies the very cosmos.

    The Choir stumbled upon an epiphany, very suddenly and
        quite by accident. Here we stand, feet planted in the earth,
        but might the cosmos be very near us, only just above our
        heads?

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Crow_Hunter_Badge">Crow Hunter Badge</itemName>
<description>Badge of a hunter of hunters, who hunts those who
        have become intoxicated by their bloodlust.
        
        The badge of the hunter of hunters is quitly
        passed down from generation to generation,
        usually to an outsider from the hinterlands.
        
        To be entrusted with this cursed badge, one must
        be strong, resilient to the seduction of blood,
        and gracious when taking a comrade's life.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Old_Hunter_Badge">Old Hunter Badge</itemName>
<description>This hunter's badge, crafted in Gehrman's time, has no
        practical purpose, except perhaps to assist in romanticising
        about the past.
        
        The badge was a special privilege for the hunters of the past,
        and should not be dishonoured.
        
        It should be left in peace, unless one is truly prepared to
        assume the will of those gone before.

        
                                                                                    


    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Powder_Keg_Hunter_Badge">Powder Keg Hunter Badge</itemName>
<description>Badge crafted by the Powder Kegs, the heretics of the
        Workshop.
        
        The Powder Kegs aboration of complex design and big
        booms culminated in weapon designs that contrast with
        those traditionally of the Workshop.
        The late Powder Kegs, bless their souls, had a motto:

        "If a weapon ain't got kick, it just ain't worth it."</description>

   

<itemName keyItemList="Radiant_Sword_Hunter_Badge">Radiant Sword Hunter Badge</itemName>
<description>One of the badges crafted by the Healing Church.
        
        The radiant sword indicates the heirs to the will of Ludwig.
        
        These hunters, also known as Holy Blades, are what remains
        of an ancient line of heroes that date back to a very early
        age of honour and chivalry.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Saw_Hunter_Badge">Saw Hunter Badge</itemName>
<description>Badge crafted long ago at the Workshop. Attests to one's
        prowess as a hunter of beasts.
        
        The Workshop is gone, and no group recognises this
        meaningless badge, except the messengers in the bath, who
        understand its profundity.
        
        Certain things can only be entrusted with a hunter in
        possession of this badge, or so they believe.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Spark_Hunter_Badge">Spark Hunter Badge</itemName>
<description>Badge crafted in secret by Archibald, the infamous eccentric
of the Healing Church, for his friends.

Archibald was fascinated by the blue sparks that emanate
from the hides of the darkbeasts, and dedicated his life to its
artificial reproduction, in a style of inquiry that, incidentally,
closely followed the methodology of Byrgenwerth.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Sword_Hunter_Badge">Sword Hunter Badge</itemName>
<description>One of the badges crafted by the Healing Church.
The silver sword is a symbol of a Church hunter.

Ludwig was the first of many Healing Church hunters to


         
                                                                                   


come, many of whom were clerics. As it was, clerics
transformed into the most hideous beasts.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Wheel_Hunter_Badge">Wheel Hunter Badge</itemName>
<description>Martyr Logarius led a band of Executioners, and this badge
was crafted at their dedicated workshop. The wheel
symbolizes righteous destiny.

Their workshop was a secretive enclave of mystical beliefs
and heady fanaticism which served as the backbone of the
Executioners' unique brand of justice.

Badge crafted by the Oto Workshop, precursor to the
workshop of the heretical Powder Kegs.

The Powder Kegs were driven by singular ideas, and crafted
strange weapons of great intricacy.
It is clear that the philosophy of the Powder Kegs was
already established at this time.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Cainhurst_Summons">Cainhurst Summons</itemName>
<description>An old blood-stained summons, inviting an honored guest
to the forsaken Castle Cainhurst.

Rather bafflingly, it is addressed to you.

Do not hesitate; the stagecoach leaves from Hemwick crossing.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Hunter_Chief_Emblem">Hunter Chief Emblem</itemName>
<description>A cloth emblem that belonged to the captain of the Church
hunters long ago. Opens the main gate that leads to the
round plaza of the Great Cathedral.

The main gate is shut tight on nights of the hunt, and could
only be opened from the other side with this emblem. In
other words, the captain's return, and this
emblem, determined the end of the hunt.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Iron_Door_Key">Iron Door Key</itemName>
<description>Of the three great bridges that link the two cathedral
cradles, this key opens the iron door that leads to the
midlevel bridge.

There are no thieves in the nightmare. Then, why lock a


        
                                                                                    


door? Be warned, there must be a very, very good reason.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Lecture_Theatre_Key">Lecture Theatre Key</itemName>
<description>Key to the Lecture Theatre in the Lecture Building.

Today, the two-story Lecture Building is adrift in the
nightmare, but once it was a place of reflection, where
scholars learned of history and archaeology.

Perhaps it still is, as the students in the lecture theatre
appear to await the return of their professor.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Lunarium_Key">Lunarium Key</itemName>
<description>Key to the lunarium facing the lake on the second floor of
Byrgenwerth College.

In his final years, Master Willem was fond of the lookout,
and the rocking chair that he kept there for meditation.
In the end, it is said, he left his secret with the lake.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Oedon_Tomb_Key">Oedon Tomb Key</itemName>
<description>Key to the gate that blocks the Tomb of Oedon.

Beyond the tomb, Oedon Chapel can be found in the center
of the Cathedral Ward.

Only today the church is abandoned, and some say that the
residents of Oedon have all gone mad.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Old_Hunter_Bell">Old Hunter Bell</itemName>
<description>One of the resonating bells that cross the gaps of worlds.
This bell is cracked and stained with the blood of beasts.

A human must expend Insight to ring this uncanny bell.

The old hunters, who have long passed from the dream but
cannot forget the feeling of the hunt, rely upon messengers
to relay their thoughts.
Ring the bell at their side, and they are certain to give a listen.
For the night of the hunt is long, and unchanging.




         
                                                                                           


    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Orphanage_Key">Orphanage Key</itemName>
<description>Key to the Orphanage, birthplace of the Choir.

The Orphanage, shadowed by the Grand Cathedral, was a
place of scholarship and experimentation, where young
orphans became potent unseen thinkers for the Healing
Church.

The Choir, that would later split from the Healing Church,
was a creation of the Orphanage.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Queenly_Flesh">Queenly Flesh</itemName>
<description>What remains of Annalise, blood queen of Cainhurst.

This pinkish lump of flesh remains warm, as if cursed.
All hail the undying queen of blood!

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Ring_of_Betrothal">Ring of Betrothal</itemName>
<description>The inhuman beings known as the Great Ones imbued this
ring of betrothal with some special meaning.

In the age of the Great Ones, wedlock was a blood contract,
only permitted to those slated to bear a special child.
</description>


<itemName keyItemList="Small_Hair_Ornament">Small Hair Ornament</itemName>
<description>A small, very ordinary hair ornament.

Although it has been lost for quite some time, one can still
see signs of the care with which this tasteful ornament was
once kept.

Its colour would stand out most brilliantly against a head of
greyish hair.




        
                                                                                    


    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Tonsil_Stone">Tonsil Stone</itemName>
<description>A latticed, deformed rock, or perhaps a meteorite.

Appears useless, but possesses some old gravitational force that prevents its riddance. A dubious soul once said:


"Step lightly round to the right of the great cathedral, and
seek an ancient, shrouded church... The gift of the godhead
will grant you strength..."

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Unopened_Summons">Unopened Summons</itemName>
<description>An old, sealed summons.

Like the first of its kind, it is an invitation to Cainhurst, but
for whom is not known, as it lacks addressee.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Upper_Cathedral_Key">Upper Cathedral Key</itemName>
<description>The key to the Upper Cathedral Ward seal.

The upper echelons of the Healing Church are formed by the
School of Mensis, based in the Unseen Village, and the Choir
occupying the Upper Cathedral Ward.

This key brings one a step closer to the Choir.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Yharnam_Stone">Yharnam Stone</itemName>
<description>A sacred heirloom left by Yharnam, Pthumerian Queen.

The Queen lies dead, but her horrific consciousness
is only asleep, and stirs in unsettling motions.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Astral_Clocktower_Key">Astral Clocktower Key</itemName>
<description>Key to the Astral Clocktower at the top of the Grand
Cathedral.

The caretaker of the tower's numerous patients, known to
them only as Lady Maria, made her home behind the giant
star-interpreting clock.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Balcony_Key">Balcony Key</itemName>
<description>Key to the balcony on the first floor of the Research Hall.

Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower gave this to the patient,
Adeline.

Maria had hoped Adeline would find comfort in the faint


         
                                                                                    


breeze that carried the scent of flowers from the outside, but
Adeline couldn't fathom her intentions.</description>

    <itemName keyItemList="First_Brain_Fluid">First Brain Fluid</itemName> <description> Greyish amoeba-shaped brain fluid. Wobbles and bounces.

Extracted from a patient whose head expanded until that
was all that they were.

In the early days of the Healing Church, the Great Ones were
linked to the ocean, and so the cerebral patients would imbibe
water, and listen for the howl of the sea. Brain fluid writhed
inside the head, the initial makings of internal eyes.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Second_Brain_Fluid">Second Brain Fluid</itemName>
<description>Greyish amoeba-shaped brain fluid. Wobbles and bounces.

Extracted from a patient whose head expanded until that
was all that they were.

Once, a young girl had an older brother who was determined to
become a doctor, and so she wilfully became his patient. In the
end, this led to their encounter with the Eldritch Truth,
for which they considered themselves blessed.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Adeline's_Brain_Fluid">Adeline’s Brain Fluid</itemName>
<description>Greyish amoeba-shaped brain fluid. Wobbles and bounces.

Extracted from a patient whose head expanded until that
was all that they were.

We fail to realize our own latent potential, until the
moment it is lost, and we sense its absence. Ironically,
this is the very nature of insight, like the moment one
licks one's own blood, only to be startled by its sweetness.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Celestial_Dial">Celestial Dial</itemName>
<description>A celestial dial that functions with the giant Astral Clock in
the Grand Cathedral.

When the dial is held up towards the Astral Clock, the clock
will come to life, and reveal a secret to its curious interloper.




         
                                                                                      


    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Eye_of_a_blood_drunk_Hunter">Eye of a blood-drunk Hunter</itemName>
<description>The eye of a blood-drunk hunter. Its pupil is collapsed and
turned to mush, indicating the onset of the scourge of beasts.

A hunter who goes drunk with blood is said to be taken by
the Nightmare, destined to wander forever, engaged in an
endless hunt. It is a fate that no hunter can escape.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Eye_Pendant">Eye Pendant</itemName>
<description>An eye pendant which unlocks the surgery altar.

There are two cathedrals in the Hunter's Dream. One lies
past the River of Blood, and another contains the private
research hall of the Healing Church.

Only chosen members of the Healing Church, or their
lamentable patients, can enter the research hall, using this
eye.

Grant eyes to the surgery altar skull.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Laurence's_Skull">Laurence’s Skull</itemName>
<description>Skull of Laurence, first vicar of the Healing Church.
In reality he became the first cleric beast, and his human
skull only exists within the Nightmare.

The skull is a symbol of Laurence's past, and what he failed
to protect. He is destined to seek his skull, but even if he
found it, it could never restore his memories.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Underground_Cell_Inner_Chamber_Key">Underground Cell Inner Chamber Key</itemName>
<description>Key to the inner chamber of the cell below the Grand
Cathedral.

The innermost chamber of the underground cell holds a lone
madman. He wears a beast hide, and rings a bell that emits
no sound.

Unending death awaits those who can hear the soundless
bell.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Underground_Cell_Key">Underground Cell Key</itemName>
<description>Key to the cell below the Grand Cathedral.

Hunters are held within the underground cell, so that things


        
                                                                                   


better left unseen, and knowledge better left unknown, will
decay quietly in the fallow darkness.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Blood_Gem_Workshop_Tool">Blood Gem Workshop Tool</itemName>
<description>A misplaced workshop tool from the Hunter's Dream.

The hunter who retrieves this can fortify weapons by
kneading blood gems into them.

Blood gems add properties to weapons when used to
fortify them, as blood defines an organism.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Rune_Workshop_Tool">Rune Workshop Tool</itemName>
<description>Runesmith Caryll, student of Byrgenwerth, transcribed the
inhuman utterings of the Great Ones into what are now
called Caryll Runes.

The hunter who retrieves this workshop tool can etch Caryll
Runes into the mind to attain their wondrous strength.

Provost Willem would have been proud of Caryll's runes, as
they do not rely upon blood in any measure.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Workshop_Haze_Extractor">Workshop Haze Extractor</itemName>
<description>A misplace workshop tool from the Hunter's Dream.

The hunter who retrieves this can extract Arcane Haze
from ritual materials.

But alas, spent materials are lost.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Black_Messenger_Hat">Black Messenger Hat</itemName>
<description>Hat that messengers are oddly fond of.
Symbol of the preventative hunters of
the Healing Church.

The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an
interest in adornment. Why not let them be happy,
and revel as babes?

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Blood_Messenger_Head_Bandage">Blood Messenger Head Bandage</itemName>
<description>Accessory adored by naive messengers imitating
the bandages of scourge victims, unaware of their meaning.
The spatters of blood give it a particularly
nice touch.


        
                                                                                   


The inhabitants of the stomp appear to have an
interest in adornment. Why not let them be happy,
and revel as babes?

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Messenger_Head_Bandage">Messenger Head Bandage</itemName>
<description>Accessory adored by naїve messengers imitating the
bandages of scourge victims, unaware of their meaning.

The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in
adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Messenger_Top_Hat">Messenger Top Hat</itemName>
<description>Hat that messengers are oddly fond of.

A nice top hat rounds out any Yharnam gentleman.

The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in
adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Messenger_Urn_Festival">Messenger Urn Festival</itemName>
<description>Accessory adored by naїve messengers.

The messengers wear the urns, filled with incense that wards
off beasts, on their heads upside-down, suggesting a
predilection to the dark.

The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in
adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Red_Messenger_Ribbon">Red Messenger Ribbon</itemName>
<description>Red ribbon that messengers are oddly fond of.

The thick, pungent red was drawn from the organs
of some unfortunate victim.

A strange choice indeed, but perhaps for the messengers
wearing this accessory constitutes a form of mourning.

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="White_Messenger_Ribbon">White Messenger Ribbon</itemName>
<description>White ribbon that messengers are oddly fond of.

A ribbon made of fine lace that shines remarkably,
more suited to pretty young girls than silly old
messengers.



        
                                                                                     


    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Worn_Messenger_Top_Hat">Worn Messenger Top Hat</itemName>
<description>A worn, rumpled top hat that messengers are oddly fond of.

The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in
adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?

    </description>

<itemName keyItemList="Yharnam_Messenger_Hat">Yharnam Messenger Hat</itemName>
<description>Hat that messengers are oddly fond of.

Commonly called a Yharnam hat.

The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest
in adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as
babes?
</description>
</keyItem>

<consumables>
<itemName consumableList="Antidote">Antidote</itemName>
    <description>Small medicinal tablets that counteract poison.
        
        <use>Used to treat ashen blood,</use> the baffling sickness that ravaged
        Old Yharnam long ago.
        
        <use>These tablets only provide short-term relief.</use> The ashen blood
        ailment eventually triggered the spread of the beastly
        scourge.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Beast_Blood_Pellet">Beast Blood Pellet</itemName>
 <description>Large medicinal pellets, supposedly formed of coagulated
beast blood. Banned by the Healing Church due to
their unclear origin. <use>Grants a spurt of beasthood.</use>

Ripping apart the flesh of one's enemies and being
rained upon by their splattering blood invigorates
one's sense of beasthood, feeding strength and
euphoric feeling alike.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Blood_of_Adella">Blood of Adella</itemName>
    <description>Blood taken from Adella, nun of the Healing Church.
        <use>Restores an amount of HP, then continues to gradually
            restore HP for a short time.</use>

The Healing Church nuns are chosen for their merit as
vessels for blood, and groomed as Blood Saints.


        
                                                                                   


The mere chance of being treated with their blood lends
legitimacy to the Healing Church and communion.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Blood_of_Arianna">Blood of Arianna</itemName>
    <description> Blood taken from Arianna, Cathedral Ward woman of
        pleasure. <use>The sweet blood of Arianna restores HP, and
            temporarily speeds stamina recovery.</use>

A member of the old Healing Church would know that her
blood is similar to precisely what was once forbidden.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Blood_Vial">Blood Vial</itemName>
        <description>Special blood used in ministration. 
            
            <use>Restores HP.</use>

Once a patient has had their blood ministered, a unique but
common treatment in Yharnam, successive infusions recall
the first, and are all the more invigorating for it.

No surprise that most Yharnamites are heavy users of blood.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Great_One’s_Wisdom">Great One’s Wisdom</itemName>
            <description>Fragments of the lost wisdom of the Great Ones, beings that
might be described as gods.

                <use>Use to gain Insight. </use>

At Byrgenwerth, Master Willem had an epiphany:

"We are thinking on the basest of planes. What we need, are
more eyes." </description>

    <itemName consumableList="Iosefka’s_Blood_Vial">Iosefka’s Blood Vial</itemName>
    <description>Blood vial acquired from Iosefka's clinic.

        <use>This refined blood, highly invigorating,
            restores a larger amount of HP.</use>

The product of a slow and careful refinement process,
this rare blood vial appears to be a clinic original.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Madman’s_Knowledge">Madman’s Knowledge</itemName>
    <description>Skull of a madman touched by the wisdom of
the Great Ones.

        <use>Use to gain Insight.</use>
        
Making contact with eldritch wisdom is a blessing,
for even if it drives one mad,
it allows one to serve a grander purpose, for posterity.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Sedatives">Sedatives</itemName>
    <description>Liquid medicine concocted at Byrgenwerth.

        <use>Calms the nerves.</use>

Those who delve into the arcane fall all-too-easily
to madness, and thick human blood serves to calm
the frayed nerves of these inquisitive minds. Naturally,
this often leads to a reliance on blood ministration.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Workshop_Third_Umbilical_Cord">Workshop Third Umbilical Cord</itemName>
    <description>A great relic, also known as the Cord of the Eye. Every
infant Great One has this precursor to the umbilical cord.

Every Great One loses its child, and then yearns for a surrogate. The Third Umbilical Cord
precipitated the encounter with the pale moon, which beckoned the hunters and conceived the
hunter's dream.

        <use>Use to gain Insight and, so they say, eyes on the inside,</use> although no one remembers what that
truly entails.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Arianna’s_Third_Umbilical_Cord">Arianna’s Third Umbilical Cord</itemName>
    <description>A great relic, also known as the Cord of the Eye. Every
infant Great One has this precursor to the umbilical cord.

Every Great One loses its child, and then yearns for a surrogate, and Oedon, the formless Great
One, is no different. To think, it was corrupted blood that began this eldritch liaison.

        <use>Use to gain Insight and, so they say, eyes on the inside,</use> although no one remembers what that
truly entails.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Iosefka’s_Third_Umbilical_Cord">“Iosefka’s” Third Umbilical Cord</itemName>
    <description>A great relic, also known as the Cord of the Eye. Every
infant Great One has this precursor to the umbilical cord.

Provost Willem sought the Cord in order to elevate his being and thoughts to those of a Great
One, by lining his brain with eyes. The only choice, he knew, if man were to ever match Their
greatness.</description>




        
                                                                                        


    <itemName consumableList="Mergo’s_Third_Umbilical_Cord">Mergo’s Third Umbilical Cord</itemName>
    <description> A great relic, also known as the Cord of the Eye. Every infant
Great One has this precursor to the umbilical cord.

Every Great One loses its child, and then yearns for a surrogate. This Cord granted Mensis
audience with Mergo, but resulted in the stillbirth of their brains.

        <use>Use to gain Insight and, so they say, eyes on the inside,</use> although no one remembers what that
truly entails.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Blood_of_Adeline">Blood of Adeline</itemName>
    <description>Blood taken from Adeline, patient of the research hall.
        <use>Restores HP, and continues to rejuvenate HP for some time.</use>

Adeline was originally one of the Blood Saints who received
treatment by the Church to cultivate worthy blood. Adeline's
was one of the few cases that turned out favorably.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Lead_Elixir">Lead Elixir</itemName>
    <description>A heavy, syrupy liquid medicine.
        <use>Temporarily shifts weight to make deflection of attacks
            easier, but must be used with care, as it also slows
            movement with no change to defense.</use>

Its recipe for this mysterious concoction is unknown, but
some postulate that it materializes only within the most
desperate nightmares.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Blue_Elixir">Blue Elixir</itemName>
    <description> Dubious liquid medicine used in strange experiments
conducted by high ministers of the Healing Church.

A type of anesthetic that numbs the brain.

Hunters, able to retain consciousness by force of will, make
use of a secondary effect of the medicine, which dilutes their
presence while standing still.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Bold_Hunter’s_Mark">Bold Hunter’s Mark</itemName>
    <description>Dubious liquid medicine used in strange experiments
conducted by high ministers of the Healing Church.

A type of anesthetic that numbs the brain.

Hunters, able to retain consciousness by force of will, make


        
                                                                                       


use of a secondary effect of the medicine, which dilutes their
presence while standing still.</description>

    <itemName consumableList="Hunter’s_Mark">Hunter’s Mark</itemName>
    <description>Dangling, upside-down rune etched in one's mind.
Symbol of a hunter.

By focusing one's thoughts on this rune, a hunter
loses all Blood Echoes, but awakens afresh,
as if it were all just a bad dream.</description>
</consumables>

<weaponBuffs>Weapon Buffs
<itemName buffList="Bolt Paper">Bolt Paper</itemName>
 <description>Coarse paper that applies bolt to weapons when rubbed.

Invented by Archibald, the infamous eccentric of the Healing
Church workshop. Artificially recreates the blue sparks that
are said to surround darkbeasts.

Unlike the other strange weapons created by Archibald, this
one was favored by many hunters, in particular those who
had even once laid eyes on a darkbeast.</description>

<itemName buffList="Bone_Marrow_Ash">Bone Marrow Ash</itemName>
    <description>Additional medium that strengthens Quicksilver Bullets.

According to the workshop, this is a special bone marrow
ash collected from Hemwick Charnel Lane.

Invaluable to hunters with weak bloodtinge who require the use of stronger firearms.</description>

<itemName buffList="Fire_Paper">Fire Paper</itemName>
    <description>Coarse paper that applies fire to weapons when rubbed.

A hunter tool found in the Healing Church workshop.

Since the tragedy that struck Old Yharnam, fire has become
a staple in beast hunts, and is thought to cleanse impurity.

Certain types of beasts have an abnormal fear of flame.</description>

</weaponBuffs>
</lore>