<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="mainSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>
<lore>
<onlineItems>Online Items
    <itemName onlineItem="Beckoning_Bell">Beckoning Bell:</itemName> <description>Great Old Bell discovered in the underground labyrinth.
    
    
    Its ring resonates across worlds, and the first hunter used it
    as a special signal to call hunters from other worlds to cross
    the gap and cooperate.
    
    
    A human must use Insight to ring this uncanny bell, but the
    benefits of cross-world cooperation are many.
    
    
    Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.
    </description>
    <itemName onlineItem="League_Staff">League Staff:</itemName> <description> The League staff is the sign of a confederate.
    
   
    A directory within the hilt lists the names of fellow
    confederates.
    
    
    Members of the League brandish this staff to indicate
    themselves to fellow members of the League.
    
    
    <page n="84"></page>
    
    
    There shall be no sympathy for those engaged in the bloody
    mission of the League. No matter that an oath must be taken
    to uphold the illusion.
    </description>
    
    <itemName onlineItem="Notebook">Notebook:</itemName><description> Messengers are inhabitants of the dream who revere the
    brave hunters. Use them to send messages to other worlds.
        
    Leave notes with messengers, read the notes left by
    messengers in other worlds, and rate notes to participate
    in the formation of a shared inter-plane intelligence.
   
    Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.
    </description>
    <itemName onlineItem="Silencing_Blank">Silencing Blank:</itemName> <description> Hunters are linked by the resonance of bells with special
    encoded timbres. This inaudible burst disrupts such
    resonance.
    
    Fire to end co-operation, and prevent further co-operation.
    Firing this does not disrupt the resonance of a sinister bell.
    
    Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.
    </description>
   
    <itemName onlineItem="Sinister_Resonant_Bell">Sinister Resonant Bell:</itemName> <description> A blood-stained bell discovered in the old underground
    labyrinth.
    
    
    One of the resonating bells that cross the gaps of worlds, but
    this one knells for misfortune and malice.
    
    The Sinister Bell is an object of dark thoughts. Ring it to
    become the enemy of a hunter in another world.
    
    Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.
    </description>
    <itemName onlineItem="Small_Resonant_Bell">Small Resonant Bell:</itemName><description> Small bell discovered in the old underground labyrinth.
    
    
    Its ring resonates across worlds, and the first hunter
    used it as a special signal to call hunters from other
    worlds to cross the gap and cooperate.
    
    This bell resonates with its counterpart, the Beckoning
    
    
    
    <page n="85"></page>
    
    
    Bell. Ring to help hunters in other worlds.
    
    Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.
    </description>
    <itemName onlineItem="Vileblood_Register">Vileblood Register:</itemName> <description>Red-leather record of the Vilebloods loyal to the covenant of
    Annalise, Queen of the Vilebloods, at Cainhurst Castle.
    
    A record of the Vilebloods, blood-lusting hunters who seek
    blood dregs of their prey, kept throughout the ages.
    
    Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.
    </description>
</onlineItems>
    
    <chaliceRitualMaterials> Chalice Ritual Materials
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Arcane_Haze">Arcane Haze:</itemName><description> Material used in a Holy Chalice rite.
    
        
    The tiny smatterings of haze that are found in certain
    ritual materials. Sometimes required for special rites.
    
    The additional rite Sinister Bell makes the bell-ringing
    woman appear, and when she rings a sinister bell, hunters
    from other worlds will be beckoned as adversaries.
            </description>
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Bloodshot_Eyeball">Bloodshot Eyeball:</itemName><description> Material used in a Holy Chalice rite.
    
        
    An exquisite eyeball removed quickly after death,
    or perhaps even before. Used to unlock the seal
    of the old labyrinth hintertombs.
    </description>
    
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Blooming_Coldbood_Flower">Blooming Coldbood Flower:</itemName> <description>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.
    
        
    Pale vegetation that commonly grows on coldblood in a
    place long abandoned, that has bloomed into a bright red
    stygian flower.
    </description>
    
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Coldblood_Flowerbud">Coldblood Flowerbud:</itemName> <description>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.
    
        
    Pale vegetation that commonly grows on coldblood in a
    place long ago abandoned.
    </description>
    
    
    <page n="86"></page>
    
    
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Coldblood_Flower_Bulb">Coldblood Flower Bulb:</itemName> <description>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.
    
        
    Pale vegetation that commonly grows on coldblood in a
    place long abandoned, said to mature slowly in close
    proximity to death, and eventually bloom.
    </description>
        
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Pearl_Slug">Pearl Slug:</itemName><description> Material used in a Holy Chalice rite.
    
        
    Of the all the strange lifeforms that reside in
    the nooks and crannies of the old labyrinth,
    the slugs are clear signs of the left-behind Great Ones.
    </description>
        
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Red_Jelly">Red Jelly:</itemName> <description>Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.
    
        
    Stillborn infants born of a creature of unknown origin, of the
    type found in some corners of the old labyrinth.
            </description>
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Ritual_Blood">Ritual Blood:</itemName> <description>Material used in a Holy Chalice rite.
    
        
    One of the basic ingredients used to satiate a Holy Chalice is this
    incoagulable blood.
    
    When all is melted in blood, all is reborn.
    </description>
        
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Tomb_Mold">Tomb Mold:</itemName><description> Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.
    
        
    Mould that grows from rotten flesh and blood inside the old
    labyrinth. Matures to bear giant spores.
    </description>
        
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Bastard_of_Loran">Bastard of Loran:</itemName><description> Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.
    
        
    Remains of Loran infant infected by the scourge.
    A harbinger of curses and symbol of defilement.
    
    The additional rite Curse defiles dungeons in which hunters'
    HP is greatly eroded, but what better place to seek cursed
    blood gems but in the midst of defilement?
    </description>
    
    
    
    
    <page n="87"></page>
    
    
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Inflicted_Organ">Inflicted Organ:</itemName> <description>Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.
    
        
    Special body parts collected by the Healing Church.
    What was this gruesome bait used to lure?
    
    The additional rite Rotted Offering beckons ungodly forces,
    normally terrifying things, but also worthy prey for a special
    hunt.
    </description>
        
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Living_String">Living String:</itemName><description> Special material used in a holy chalice ritual.
    
        
    The immense brain that Mensis retrieved from the nightmare
    was indeed lined with eyes on the inside, but they were of
    an evil sort, and the brain itself was terrible rotten.
    
    But even still, it was a legitimate Great One, and left a relic.
    A living relic, at that, which is a precious thing indeed.
    </description>
    
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Sage’s_Hair">Sage's Hair:</itemName> <description>Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.
    
        
    A body part of a saint, sacrificed by the Healing Church in
    their search for Truth.
    
    The additional rite Fetid Offering invigorates the Watchers,
    making them more treacherous than normal, but also making
    them worthy prey for a special hunt.
    </description>
    
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Sage’s_Wrist">Sage's Wrist:</itemName> <description>Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.
    
        
    A body part of a saint, sacrificed by the Healing Church in
    their search for Truth.
    
    The additional rite Fetid Offering invigorates the Watchers,
    making them more treacherous than normal, but also making
    them worthy prey for a special hunt.
    </description>
    
        <itemName chaliceRitualMaterial="Yellow_Backbone">Yellow Backbone:</itemName> <description>Special material used in a Holy Chalice rite.
    
       
   Special body parts collected by the Healing Church.
    What was this gruesome bait used to lure?
    </description>
    
    </chaliceRitualMaterials>
    <page n="88"></page>
</lore>