<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<!--<?xml-model href="../documentation/mainSchema.rnc" type="application/relax-ng-compact-syntax"?>-->
<lore>
    Caryll Runes
    <caryllRune>
        <itemName runeList="Beast">Beast Rune</itemName>
        <description>A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
            
            A transcription of the roar of a labyrinth beast, the bearer of
            the "Beast" rune has accentuated transformation effects.
            
            "Beast" is one of the early Caryll Runes, as well as one of the
            first to be deemed forbidden. The discovery of blood entailed
            the discovery of undesirable beasts.</description>
    </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
        <itemName runeList="Blood_Rapture">Blood Rapture Rune</itemName>
        <description>A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
            "Blood Rapture" is the raw euphoria of the warmth of blood.
            Restores HP with visceral attacks, one of the darker hunter
            techniques.
            
            This rune resonates with servants of the Queen, carrier of
            the Child of Blood, who yearn for their Queen's blood with
            little hope of requitement.
            
            For them, they find solace in "Blood Rapture," that serves as
            a surrogate for their desires. </description>
    </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
        <itemName runeList="Clawmark">Clawmark Rune</itemName>
        <description>A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
            
            The "Clawmark" is an impulse to seek the warmth of blood
            like a beast. It strengthens visceral attacks, one of the darker
            hunter techniques.
            
            Although the difference is subtle, Runesmith Caryll describes
            the "Beast" as a horrific and unwelcome instinct deep within
            the hearts of men, while "Clawmark" is an alluring invitation
            to accept this very nature. </description>
    </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
        <itemName runeList="Communion">Communion Rune</itemName>
        <description>A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
            
            Several runes relate to "blood," including "Communion,"
            which raises the maximum number of blood vials
            one may carry. 
            
            
            
            
            
            
            This rune represents the Healing Church and its
            ministers. Blood ministration is, of course, the pursuit
            of communion. </description>
    </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>      
        <itemName runeList="Eye">Eye Rune</itemName>
        <description>A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
            
            A transcription of "eye," as spoken by left-behind Great
            Ones. Allows one to make additional discoveries.
            
            Eyes symbolize the truth Master Willem sought in his
            research. Disillusioned by the limits of human intellect,
            Master Willem looked to beings from higher planes for
            guidance, and sought to line his brain with eyes in order to
            elevate his thoughts. </description>
    </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
        <itemName runeList="Formless_Oedon">Formless Oedon Rune</itemName> 
        <description>A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
            
            The Great One Oedon, lacking form, exists only in voice,
            and is symbolised by this rune. Those who memorise it enjoy
            a larger supply of Quicksilver Bullets.
            
            Human or no, the oozing blood is a medium of the highest
            grade, and the essence of the formless Great One, Oedon.
            Both Oedon, and his inadvertent worshippers, surreptitiously
            seek the precious blood. </description>
    </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Heir">Heir Rune</itemName>
    <description>A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
        
        The "Heir" sees sentimentality in the warmth of blood, and
        acknowledges visceral attacks as one of the darker hunter
        techniques.
        
        More blood echoes gained from visceral attacks.
        
        Perhaps the "Heir" is a hunter who bears the echoing will of
        those before him. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Moon">Moon Rune</itemName>
    <description>A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        
        A transcription of "moon," as spoken by the Great Ones
        inhabiting the nightmare.
        
        Gain more Blood Echoes.
        
        The Great Ones that inhabit the nightmare are
        sympathetic in spirit, and often answer when called upon. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Oedon_Writhe">Oedon Writhe Rune </itemName>
    <description>A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
        
        "Writhe" sees a subtle mucous in the warmth of blood,
        and acknowledges visceral attacks as one of the darker hunter
        techniques. Visceral attacks restore Quicksilver Bullets.
        
        Human or no. the oozing blood is a medium of the highest
        grade, and the essence of the formless Great One, Oedon.
        Both Oedon, and Oedon's inadvertent worshippers,
        surreptitiously seek the precious blood. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Guidance">Guidance Rune</itemName>
    <description>A Caryll rune discovered by the old hunter Ludwig along
        with the Holy Moonlight Sword.
        Boosts amount of life recovered by rallying.
        
        When Ludwig closed his eyes, he saw darkness, or perhaps
        nothingness, and that is where he discovered the tiny beings
        of light. Ludwig was certain that these playful dancing
        sprites offered "guidance," and emptied Ludwig of his fears
        at least in the midst of a hunt. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Lake">Lake Rune</itemName> 
    <description>A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        
        This transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices
        ripples like a watery reflection. This rune means "Lake,"
        and those branded by it enjoy augmented defense.
        
        Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark guarding sleep,
        and an augur of the eldritch Truth.
        
        Overcome this hindrance, and seek what is yours. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    
    
    
    
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Anti-Clockwise_Metamorphosis">Anti-Clockwise Metamorphosis Rune</itemName>
    <description>A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of
        Byrgenwerth.
        
        The twisted cross means "metamorphosis."
        
        Rotated anti-clockwise, this rune boosts stamina.
        
        The discovery of blood made their dream of evolution
        a reality, Metamorphosis, and the excesses and deviation
        that followed, was only the beginning. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Clockwise_Metamorphosis">Clockwise Metamorphosis Rune</itemName> 
    <description>A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        
        The twisted cross means "metamorphosis."
        
        Rotated clockwise, this rune boosts HP.
        
        The discovery of blood made their dream of evolution
        a reality. Metamorphosis, and the excesses and deviation
        that followed. were only the beginning. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Sea">Sea Rune</itemName> 
    <description>A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
        
        This transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices depicts
        downreaching currents. This rune means "Deep Sea," and
        grants augmented resistance.
        
        Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark guarding sleep,
        and an augur of the eldritch Truth.
        
        Overcome this hindrance, and seek what is yours. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Corruption">Corruption Rune</itemName> 
    <description>A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        
        Several runes contain a nuance of "Blood," including the
        rune of "Corruption," associated with the oath of the corrupt.
        
        Pledgers to this oath are Cainhurst Vilebloods, hunters of
        blood who find dregs for their Queen in coldblood,
        particularly in that of hunters.
        
        
        
        
        
        
        Yet the corrupt are heretics in the eyes of the Church, and
        thus subject to the wrath of the Executioners. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Hunter">Hunter Rune</itemName>
    <description>A Caryll Rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
        
        This red-smudged rune means "Hunter," and has been
        adopted by those who have taken the Hunter of Hunters oath.
        These watchmen admonish those who have become addled
        with blood. Be they men or beasts, anyone who has
        threatened the pledgers of the "Hunter" oath surely has an
        issue with blood. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Impurity">Impurity Rune</itemName> 
    <description>A Carryl rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
        This rune, discovered inside the forbidden beast eater, came
        to symbolize "Impurity," and the oath of the League.
        
        Confederates of The League cooperate with hunters from
        other worlds, and hunt to discover vermin.
        Vermin writhe within filth, and are the root of man's
        impurity. Crush all vermin without hesitation. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Radiance">Radiance Rune</itemName> 
    <description>A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.
        
        The rune for "Radiance," adopted by the sworn
        Executioners under Logarius' command.
        
        The executioners despise the impure Vilebloods,
        and no matter what the circumstances, would
        never cooperate with the bloodthirsty hunters
        who serve the undead queen, Annalise. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    <caryllRune>
    <itemName runeList="Beast's_Embrace">Beast’s Embrace Rune</itemName>
    <description>After repeated experiments in controlling the scourge of
        beasts, the gentle "Embrace" rune was discovered.
        
        When its implementation failed, the "Embrace" became a
        forbidden rune, but its knowledge became a foundation of
        the Healing Church.
        
        Those who swear this oath take on a ghastly form, and enjoy
        accentuated transformation effects, especially while wielding a beast weapon. </description>
        </caryllRune>
    
    
    
    
    <caryllRune>
        <itemName runeList="Milkweed">Milkweed Rune</itemName> 
        <description>A Caryll rune envisioned by Adeline, patient of the
            research hall.
            
            A transcription of the inhuman, sticky whispers that reveal
            the nature of a celestial attendant.
            Those who take this oath become a lumenwood that peers
            towards the sky, feeding phantasms in its luscious bed.
            Phantasms guide us and lead us to further discoveries. </description>
        
    </caryllRune>
</lore>

