<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<root>
Script 1




                Bloodborne Script
                          1
                              (All Bloodborne Item Descriptions, Dialogue and Notes)


                                               Dialogue

Blood Minister: Good. All signed and sealed. Now, let's begin the transfusion. Oh, don't you
worry. Whatever happens... You may think it all a mere bad dream...

Now, let’s begin the transfusion.

Iosefka: Are you... out on the hunt? Then I'm very sorry, but... I cannot open this door. I am
Iosefka. The patients here in my clinic must not be exposed to infection. I know that you hunt for
us, for our town, but I'm sorry. Please. This is all that I can do.

Now, go. And good hunting.

Are you still in need of something? But I have nothing more to offer. Please, try to understand
my position. I can only pray, for a fruitful hunt.

You are safe, thank goodness. But I'm afraid nothing will change. I cannot open the door. I'll do
what I can, of course. Perhaps this will help you, if only in some small way.

Now, go. I pray for your safety.

You are safe, thank goodness. But I'm afraid nothing will change. I cannot open the door. I'll do
what I can, of course. Perhaps this will help you, if only in some small way.

This night is long, but morning always comes. Someone of your caliber won't fail us, I am
certain. And once the night of the hunt ends, we can speak face-to-face. Then I can finally see
what you look like. I shouldn't be thinking this but I am rather looking forward to it. So please,
be careful out there.

I'm sorry...I have nothing else to offer you. I will pray for your safety. May light shine upon this
night, and your fortunes.

1
    To find Specific things press Ctrl + F

            ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                Script 2



Ah oh.

Please stop! It's beasts you hunt. Why are you behaving like one? This can't be the real you.
Please, stop....

Are you calm again? Thank goodness. You mustn't let the hunt overcome you. Remember
yourself. You are not a beast.

You are no more than a beast. I should've known....

Eileen the Crow: Oh, a hunter, are ya? And an outsider? What a mess you've been caught up in.
And tonight, of all nights. Here, to welcome the new hunter.

Prepare yourself for the worst. There are no humans left. They're all flesh-hungry beasts, now.

Still lingering about? What's wrong? A hunter, unnerved by a few beasts? Heh heh...
No matter, without fear in our hearts, we're little different from the beasts themselves.

What are you still doing here? Enough trembling in your boots. A hunter must hunt.

Look at you, you sorry drunk. I'll string you up like the filthy beast you are. You shall not
abscond your crimes.

Were you not once a hunter? Is this sincerely what you want? That’s enough now... No one will
blame you.

The beasts cannot be stopped!

What good are hunters now?

Your blood is mine!

A hunter's blood for me!

Your punishment is death!

Death to the hunters!

Enough of this terrible dream!


         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                               Script 3



You still have dreams? Tell the little doll I said hello.

You can't go on like this…

Oh, hello there.

Perfect timing. I must warn you not to go near the tomb below Oedon Chapel in the Cathedral
Ward. Henryk, an old hunter, has gone mad. And he's my mark...

Don't go near the tomb below Oedon Chapel in the Cathedral Ward. I have business there first...

Few hunters can resist the intoxication of the hunt. Look at you, just the same as all the rest...

The hunters must die... The nightmare must end... Only I can stop this madness! The hunt makes
hunters mad!

...Ah... you monsters... All hunters must die!

That wasn't necessary of you... But you have my thanks.

We made it, with our lives. You're not bad at all. You must've killed Gascoigne as well, then? He
was falling apart. I'm sure it had to be done. But try to keep your hands clean.

A hunter should hunt beasts. Leave the hunting of hunters to me...

Oh is that you again? I'm afraid I've made a bit of a blunder. I'm just going to have a short rest.
Oh, don't worry. I've taken blood. Enough to save an old woman. No more dreams for me. This
is my last chance. What a fool I am. I'll have to tread carefully. But that thing still lies in wait.

Turn back. This is my score to settle. My prey lies in wait this way.

Don't you ever listen to your elders? No matter, you did save my life. I don't see apt for this life
anymore... ...My glory days were long ago now... Hmmm. I know... Here, for you. This too is
hunters' work, but it bears no honor. A burden you may choose to carry.

The decision is yours alone. Ahh, my eyes grow heavy... Let me rest a while...

...I'll be fine, just wait…



         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                             Script 4


Gilbert, Critically Ill Man: Oh, you must be a hunter. And... not one from around here, either.
I'm Gilbert. A fellow outsider. You must have had a fine time of it. Yharnam has a special way
of treating guests. Well, I don't think I could stand if I wanted to... But I'm willing to help, if
there's anything that can be done.

This town is cursed. Whatever your reasons might be, you should plan a swift exit. Whatever can
be gained from this place, it will do more harm than good...

Paleblood, you say? Hmm... Never heard of it. But if it's blood you're interested in, you should
try the Healing Church. The church controls all knowledge on blood ministration, and all
varieties of blood. Across the valley to the East of Yharnam Iies the town of the Healing Church,
known as the Cathedral Ward. And deep within Cathedral Ward is the old grand cathedral. ...the
birthplace of the Healing Church‘s special blood, or so they say. Yharnamites don't share much
with outsiders. Normally, they wouldn't let you near the place, but... The hunt is on tonight. This
might be your chance...

Across the vaIley to the East of Yharnam, you'll find the Cathedral Ward. Deep within lies the
old main cathedral, said to be the source of blood. I haven't heard of Paleblood, but... That's your
best bet if it's anything to do with unique types of blood...

Yes, I see... But the great bridge is the only way to the Cathedral Ward. And during the hunt, the
bridge is closed... Hmm... You could try the aqueduct? There's a rather, how shall I put it,
colorful area south of the great bridge. From there, an aqueduct leads to the Cathedral Ward. Not
a place you'd normally want to visit, but... I don't imagine you have much of a choice. Do you?

An aqueduct leads from the town, south of the main bridge to the Cathedral Ward. Not a place
you'd normally choose to visit, but... Not much of a choice, with the bridge closed...
Have I heard of Byrgenwerth? Hmm... Afraid I can't say that I have. The locals aren't apt to share
any local history. I'm afraid I may not be of help for much longer...

Hmm... I know nothing of a Byrgenwerth, and I'm afraid I may not be of help for much longer.
Ahh, you needn't concern yourself with me. I'm afraid l‘m of little help now. But before I... Take
this... I made no use of it, but perhaps you...

What afflicted me was incurable, but this town gave me hope... Their strange blood bought me
time. I was most fortunate. Unharmed by the plague of beasts. I can even die human...

Ahh, don't you worry about me.

Why... me... why... Dear gods, what have I done? Save me, please... Save me...


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                            Script 5



Mm? Is something wrong? Stop this nonsense at once. So, you've gone over the edge. A terrible
pity. Just another Yharno now.

Imposter Iosefka: Oh, well, hello....Splendid. Let me ask you a small kindness. You're soon off
to hunt, I presume? Then, if you find any survivors, tell them to seek Iosefka's Clinic.
Upon my Hippocratic oath, if they are yet human, I will look after them, perhaps even cure them.

This sickness, these beasts, they are not to be feared. This time the night is long. I might be
trapped here, but I should do something to help. I'll even offer a reward for your cooperation.
Tempted? Well, off you go then.

If you find anyone who’s still human, send them straight to Iosefka clinic. You can assure them,
there’s no place safer. Please do me this service.

Oh, hello. You made it. Find any survivors? Or only beasts? Tell anyone who's human about
Iosefka's Clinic. I will take proper care of them. They're in your hands, and soon, mine....

Oh hello...You're all right. Very good. She's safe with me now, I presume you're to thank? The
treatment is going well, stabilized, for the most part. Fascinating, really....Here you are, as
promised.

Oh, thank goodness you came....Be a dear, find me some more. Hehehe..

There may yet be humans out there. If you find them, send them to Iosefka's Clinic. I endeavor to
treat every survivor there is. So please, be a saint.

Oh hello.....You're safe. What a relief. He's safe with me now. I'm thrilled to have another. Here
you are, as promised.

What would I ever do without you? You're really making a difference...Hahaha

Oh, hello...You're still alive. Any luck then? Finding anyone who hasn't turned? If you do, you
know where to send them.

Ahh! Can't anyone comprehend?! That'll be quite enough of you then. Isn't it time someone put
you out of your misery?




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                 Script 6


Ah, moonlit scents....How did you worm your way in here? Well, I won't make any excuses.
Would you mind leaving us alone? Things need not change...You'll do the rescuing, and I'll do
the saving. But, if you refuse to leave...

Ah, well...I always wanted to try my hand on a hunter...

This won't hurt a bit...I'll soon have you right as rain...

Hush, hush....Stay still....This won't hurt a bit... I'll soon have you right as
rain...Just.....Die... ...Enough of you! Now, stop that!

Curse this oblivious fool…

Oh, how exciting! I've never worked on a hunter before…

Oh, hello... Still alive, are you? I need more patients... There aren't many humans left, I know,
but find me every last one you can. We must find a way. To surpass our own stupidity. You're
one of the bright ones. Don't you see how much this means?

If you find any humans, bring them to me. I'm depending on you, brave hunter.

Oh hello....You're alive. Good. I've received another patient. This time, I'll be trying old blood.
I've achieved much. And I owe it all to you. Take this, as thanks.

Custom made. And cheers, to the discovery of kinship. Doesn't it make you feel warm inside?

Please....find me some more. I'm depending on you, brave hunter.

Oh hello....You're still alive. But I suppose we're nearing the end. I don't imagine there are any
left who haven't turned by now. Tragic, really, but what's to be done....

God I'm nauseous... Have you ever felt this? It's progressing. I can see things... I knew it, I'm
different. I'm no beast... I... Oh... God, it feels awful... but, it proves that I'm chosen. Don't you
see? How they writhe, writhe inside my head... It's... rather... rapturous…

Father Gascoigne: ...Beasts all over the shop…You’ll be one of them...Sooner or later…

…What's that smell? The sweet blood, oh, it sings to me. It's enough to make a man sick...

Too proud to show your true face, eh? But a sporting hunt, it was!


         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                              Script 7


Oedon Chapel Dweller: ...Hmm? Oh... you must be... a hunter. Very sorry, the incense must've
masked your scent. Good, good. I've been waiting for one of your ilk. These hunts have everyone
all locked up inside. Waiting for it to end... It always does, always has, y'know. Since forever.

But it won't end very nicely, not this time. Even some folks hiding inside are goin' bad. The
screams of wimminfolk, the stench of blood, the snarls of beasts... none of em‘s too uncommon
now. Yharnam's done fer, I tell ya.

But if you spot anyone with their wits about ‘em... Tell ‘em about this here Oedon Chapel.
They'll be safe here. The incense wards off the beasts. Spread the word... tell ‘em to come on
over. If you wouldn't mind... Hee hee…

...Hmm? Oh... you must be... a hunter. I know I shouldn't be askin‘ you, but... If you happen
upon someone while hunting, tell ‘em about this here Oedon Chapel. If they seem worth being
told, that is... Oh, and I do sincerely hope they are... hee hee hee hee hee...

Ahh, the hunter. Alive and well, are ya? This here's a safe place. Stay as long as you like. But...
next time you're out on a hunt, remember what I asked. If you find any sane survivors, tell ‘em to
seek shelter at Oedon Chapel. Cause there's nothing to fear here... ha, hah ha!

Ahh, the hunter. Alive and well, are ya?

Ahh, the hunter! Thank you. So, that survivor, you told 'im about this place right? Well, he don't
offer me much in the way of conversation, but still... I'd rather see 'im alive anyhow. And... I sort
of hoped that, my asking you, turned out to, you know, help ‘em out in the end... I've never been
of any use to anyone, you see... Just, happy about it, is all... ha, ha

Ahh, the hunter! Thank you. So, that survivor, you told 'im about this place, right? If you find
any sane survivors, well... Send ‘em along to Oedon Chapel, will ya?

Ahh, the hunter. Alive and well, at that! Another one you sent made it here safe and sound. This
place is a haven now, for so many. Thanks to you. I'm... overjoyed, really. That you'd even give
me the time o‘ day! I don't suppose there's anybody out there worth savin' anymore. But you did
all ya could, and so many owe you so much. Amazing, really. Not ‘cause you're a hunter, but
because you're you.

Makes me think, once dawn breaks, maybe I can just, you know, start over. Makes it easier to
bear all o‘ this, you see? You've made life easier. Thank you.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                Script 8


Ahh, the hunter. Alive and well, at that! I'm... overjoyed, really. That you'd even give me the
time o' day! But you did all ya could, and so many owe you so much. Amazing, really. Not
‘cause you're a hunter, but because you're you.

If you please, kind hunter... When the night of the hunt passes, s'pose, we could be friends,
maybe? Now, I know I hardly deserve it, but... Well, I had to just, ask, you know? Out of line,
yes, perhaps so, but, well... Give it a thought, if you wouldn't mind, o' course... If you please,
kind hunter... Once the night of the hunt passes, s'pose we could be friends? Give it a thought,
well, if you wouldn't mind...

Ahh, kind hunter! Another one you sent made it here safe and sound. This place is a real haven
now. Thanks to you. ...But... I'm afraid that was the last of ‘em... There ain't a peep to be heard,
not in the whole town... I doubt there's any more out there... Gods save us... Yharnam's done
for...

Ahh, kind hunter! There ain't no more survivors, there can't be... Yharnam's done for... Oh, kind
hunter... How did this happen? A beast, here... why...? It's my fault... Savaged and eaten, every
one, and it's all my fault... Gods, please, I'm sorry, so sorry... Oh, kind hunter... I only wanted to
help... Just once in my life... They told me it would never work... My mum always told me,
everybody kept telling me... I should've known, I should've... Gods, please, I'm sorry, so sorry...

Oh, kind hunter... The man you sent here, the one you saved... e's dead... Killed stone dead...
Why... Musta been a beast, right?. ...Or, d'ya think someone out there could've... I...I... just
don't... ahh... Well. I do know. It's my fault. All mine...

Oh, kind hunter... The man you sent here, the one you saved... Was it a beast? Or, could someone
from outside‘ve come in and...? l just... don't... know...

Oh, kind hunter... Someone's died... again... Eaten... devoured by a damned beast! We're not safe
here. This is it... The end of us all...

Oh, kind hunter... We're not safe here. This is it... The end of us all... Oh, kind hunter! Thank
you. So, that lady, you told ‘er about this place? Well, she... she actually talks to me! Well, only
now and then, and... she don't mince words... But... she's a kind one, I can tell. A good woman.

Oh, kind hunter! Thank you. So, that lady, you told ‘er about this place? Oh, kind hunter! Thank
you. So, that man, you told 'im about this place? Well, he keeps ‘is distance an‘ all, but... I
reckon we're two peas in a pod. We both been put through life's wringer. I'm... I'm bloody glad
you told 'im about us.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                 Script 9


Oh, kind hunter! Thank you. So, that man, you told 'im about this place? I'm... I'm bloody glad
you told 'im about us. Stop! Please! What's the- Why! Please, good hunter! I'm beggin' ya stop...
Please, just stop... Please, good hunter! How did it come... to this... Kind... hunter... l just wanted
to help... people... I only wanted... to be... your friend...

Eeek! Please, no more! It's my fault, I know, so... help me, please... Please, kind hunter. Please,
kind hunter. Thank you.

So, that survivor, you told ‘er about this place right? Well, she don't offer me much in the way of
conversation, but still... I'd rather see ‘er alive anyhow.

The woman you sent here, the one you saved... She's dead... Killed stone dead...

So, that survivor, you told ‘er about this place, right? The woman you sent here, the one you
saved...

So, that old man, you told 'im about this place right? The old man, the old man you sent over...

So, that old girl, you told ‘er about this place right? The old girl, the old girl you sent over...

The lady, the Iady you sent over... The lady, the lady you sent over...

So, that holy woman, you told ‘er about this place right? The 'oly woman, the 'oly woman you
sent over…

Arianna, Women of Pleasure: Oh, my, what a queer scent... But I'd take it over the stench of
blood and beasts any day. What is it, then?

I'm off during hunts, so if that's what you're here for, I'll leave you to your own devices. If that
doesn't do it, come back in the morning, darling.

Oh, thank goodness. You're a hunter, right? Might you know of a safe place? The night is long,
and I've very little of the incense left... Please, there must be some nice place to run off to?

Oh, thank you, darling. Maybe I'll see you there! Oh... that's a shame. Well, if you do find a safe
place, do be a dear and tell me. Around here, you're the only one I can turn to. You understand,
don't you?

Ahh, hello there. Come to see me? Have you found any safe places?



         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                               Script 10


Oh, hello dear... You weren't lying. This is a safe place. Thank you. I'm in your debt. I'd like to
tender my thanks, but I haven't much to offer... All I can give is my blood. But... would you even
take a whore's blood?

Yes, I see... I suppose that's natural. If you ever change your mind... You know where I'll be...

Oh, good. Come close, dear. Don't worry, this isn't the first time.

Oh, hello... Sorry, dear. You're much too eager. I've only so much blood... okay?

Oh, hello... You've come for my blood? Oh, good. Come close, dear.

I knew you'd be back for more.

Oh, that's a pity. Any time you're ready.

Oh, you... I'm sorry... l'm afraid I can't help you. Unless... you've had a change of heart?

If you ever change your mind... You know where I'll be...

Oh, my, what a queer scent... But I'd take it over the stench of blood and beasts any day. What is
it, then? I'm off during hunts, and besides, this is no place for ladies. Wouldn't want to drag you
down too.

I'm off during hunts, and besides... This is no place for ladies.

Oh, thank goodness. You're a hunter, aren't you dear? Might you know of a safe place? The night
is long, and I've very little of the incense left... Please, there must be some nice place to run off
to? Oh, thank you, dear. Perhaps I'll see you there!

Oh... that's a shame. Well, if you do find a safe place, do be a dear and tell me. Around here, you
are the only one I can turn to. You understand, don't you?

Ahh, hello there. Come to see me? Have you found any safe places?

Oh, hello dear... You weren't lying. This is a safe place. Thank you. I am in your debt. I'd like to
tender my thanks, but I can't imagine what to offer. All I can give is my blood. But... would you
even take a whore's blood?

Yes, I see... I suppose that‘s natural. I won't try to tempt you.


         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                              Script 11


Oh, good. Come close, dear. Don't worry, I've done this before. Oh, hello... Sorry, dear. You're
much too eager. I've only so much blood... okay? Oh, hello... You‘ve come for my blood?

Yes, of course... I'm sorry, I ask too many questions. I'm very thankful for what you've done.

Oh, hello. The whole town's turned, has it? Quite a big family now, aren't we? Though I'm afraid
I seem to be the black sheep... Back for my blood, I presume?

Oh, there you are. Not too safe here after all, is it? But I'm not concerned. I've no better place to
go, and you were terribly kind to show me here.

Back for more of my blood, I presume? I've no better place to go, and you were terribly kind to
show me here.

Oh, there you are... Forgive me, I'm a bit out of sorts...So, no blood today, I’m afraid...

Oh, there's something wrong with me…

It can't be... this is a nightmare. I've never been happier…

Lonely Old Dear: Oh, you're a hunter, aren't ya? Then, well, do you know of any safe places?

I've heard, I have. Shutting up indoors isn't always enough. If you hunters got off your arses, we
wouldn't be in this mess. You're obligated to help me, you hear? So, what’ll it be? Are you gonna
tell me, or not?

Well, whaddya know? An outsider worth a lick of salt.

Well, don't just stand there. Don't you have work to do? Go slit some throats, get this mess done
with.

Oh, enough with you. Trot along, chop chop!

What is it now? I've much better ways to pass the time. Unless... you've found me a nice, safe
place?

Oh, no, I haven't forgotten. Do you think I owe you something? Well, that's a fine lark, I'd say.
This whole mess that Yharnam's in, it's all your fault, you fidgety outsiders! Our blood's ruined,
tainted by your ilk! Don't you come near me! I know your type!



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                          Script 12


You! Stay away from me! I know all your tricks!

Ohh, how did we ever get into this mess... Oh, the good old days, what a laugh, eh?

Oh, there you are. You're home early, dear. Is anything the matter? You can always tell me...
Mother'll make everything better...

You're home early, dear. Oh, what is it, dear? Are you in a bind again? Oh, what is it, dear? Oh,
welcome home, dear. What's wrong? Anything you'd like to tell me?

Oh, my. You poor thing... Now, now, have some patience... Mother'll make everything better...

Oh, welcome home, dear. You've been very, very patient. Here you are. This will help you
forget... Forget your troubles, forget your cares...

What a relief! You always were the brave one. But you can't bottle up everything inside. You
mustn't be afraid to share. You always were the brave one.

What's got into you! Curse you, stranger! Curse you, stranger!

Narrow-minded Man: You... you're not from around here are ya? An outsider who's come to
join the hunt? What a pathetic idea. You what? What, you think I'm a beast? Well, maybe I think
you're a beast. Well, away with ya! And step away from my Castle!

You... you're not from around here are ya? An outsider who's come to join the hunt? What a
pathetic idea. Well, away with ya! Oh, enough of you... What, you think this is funny? Well I
certainly don't. So be gone with ya! I'll have nothing to do with your beast hunts.

Oh, enough with you already. Come on, just go, will ya? What's this two-bit nonsense you're
peddlin'? I heard you told that wench about some shelter. Well, she's a damn fool to trust an
outsider. Why? Her sort's probably just fixin' to thieve some of your coin.

All right, what crafty lies does the outsider have today? You think I'm an easy mark? Yeah?
Well, give me your best shot.

Hmph... Yeah sorry, too sharp for that bollocks. I know a superstition when I hear one.
Outsiders... even their lies are predictable.

What, afraid your lies will be exposed? Yeah, I knew you'd back off, I just knew it.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                           Script 13


Yeah, an outsider, you may be, but at least you know when you're bested.

What? Still preying on folks with your book of lies? Yeah, fine, come on. Show me what you've
got. Tell me about your little safe place.

What? You just can't help yourself, can ya? Go on then, fine, go on... tell me about it. Your little
safe haven. Ah, you, the swindlin' offcomer. Did you really think that'd work? There's no fooling
me! Now, off with ya, you heard me! Go away! I can't stand the stench of your lyin' breath!

Ah, you, the swindlin' offcomer. Did you really think that'd work? There's no fooling me! Go
away! I can't stand the stench of your Iyin' breath!

I've no time for your petty lies.

Away, just away with you, now! I mean it! And don't you come back, do you hear me! Don't
come back! Oh, give it a rest, please. I've no time for your petty lies. Awa- just go away now! I
can't stand the stench of your lyin' breath!

I'll spare you one nugget of advice. Beware the lady of the night. I can see it in her eyes. She
deeply resents the young saint. She hears people whisper. She knows what people think of her.
Yes, she despises the saint for having what she doesn't. Bloody wench, they shoulda moved her
on ages ago.

I'll spare you one nugget of advice. Beware the blind man. There the beggar sits, at the bottom of
the bloody food chain… …and then he's here, acting like he owns the place... He's not to be
trusted. What's he want with all those people anyway. That little weasel has a murky past, I'm
tellin' ya...

Now, be gone! Go, away with ya! Don't ever bother me again! An outsider won't get far
behaving like that.

Ahh, your lies spin a web... But I see through your deceit! I did not learn from books. No, no, no,
no, no... I learned it all with my own mind...

Bloody offcomer... curse you...




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                Script 14


Adella, Nun of the Healing Church: Oh, merciful gods, help me... In the name of the Healing
Church, cleanse us of this horrible dream...

Please, leave me be... Don't take me... please... Oh, please, dear gods...

Ahh, by your garb... the Healing Church... You've come to save me... Ahh! Thank you, dear
saint! I have no words to express my relief... You could take this, at least. It is sure to please an
upstanding member of the church like you.

Ahh, thank you so much. I was seized on the street by a hulking brute in the Cathedral Ward and
locked up here. There were many others, but they've been taken away... And I've heard moans,
echoing in the distance, ever since...

So, the hunt is on tonight? Then the streets are perilous... And every door will be shut tight...
Perhaps it isn't my place to ask, but... Do you know somewhere that might take me in?

Oh, thank you so much. I'll set out as soon as I can. I pray for success on your hunt.

Kind hunter... I'll set out as soon as I can. I pray for success on your hunt.

Kind hunter... Yes, I see... I understand. Such are the perils on a night of the hunt. I'll ask an
acquaintance in the Cathedral Ward. Perhaps he'II open his door for me... perhaps.

You're... a hunter, aren't you? I'll be fine. I don't wish to trouble you any further. I'll ask an
acquaintance in the Cathedral Ward. Unless, y-you know of another place?

Oh, brave hunter. You're alive. Thank you very much. The town is in disarray, but there are still
people here. Together, we await the help of the Healing Church. I cannot begin to express my
gratitude to you. The only thing that I can offer... Is my own lowly blood. If it would suffice...

Oh, brave hunter. You're alive. Yes, of course. Come in close... Now... take my blood...

Brave hunter. Please, give me a little more time. There are others in need of my blood.

Brave hunter. Please, give me a little more time.

Ahh, brave hunter. You're safe. Do you wish... to have my blood?




         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                               Script 15


Ahh, brave hunter. You're safe. Forgive me, I... I should have known better. What would a brave
hunter do with lowly blood like mine? Please, forget I even asked. What would a brave hunter do
with lowly blood like mine?

Ahh, brave hunter. What is it? Have you renewed thoughts on this matter? Forgive me. I must
cease this nonsense. Forget I ever offered.

I pray for your safety.

Oh, forgive me. I need more time...

Oh, brave hunter, you‘ve returned, unharmed. Don't you want to be treated... with blood? I only
wish to be of help.

What have I done...

Tee hee... My sweet hunter... Your blood is tainted... I can't... ha... I can't help myself... hahaha
haha...

I will never leave your side…

Alfred, Hunter of Vilebloods: You're a beast hunter, aren't you? I knew it. That's precisely how
I started out! Oh, beg pardon, you may call me Alfred. Protégé of Master Logarius, hunter of
Vilebloods. So, what say you? Our prey might differ, but we are hunters, the both of us. Why not
cooperate, and discuss the things we've learned?

Oh-hoh! Very good, very good indeed! Take this, to celebrate our acquaintance. Beast hunting is
a sacred practice. May the good blood guide your way.

Well, that's most unfortunate. But, if you have a change of heart, you know where to come. We
are, after all, fellow hunters, and tonight we hunt!

Oh, changed our mind, have we? Then perhaps we can cooperate, and discuss what we've
learned. There must be oodles for us to share. Go on, just tell me what piques your interest.

Oh-hoh! Good to see you safe. Now, let's think up something to discuss. Just tell me what piques
your interest.




         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                            Script 16


As you know, the Healing Church is the fountainhead of blood healing. Well, I'm a simple
hunter, quite unfamiliar with the ins and outs of the institution. But I have heard that the holy
medium of blood healing is venerated in the main cathedral. And that

councilors of the old church reside in the high stratum of the Cathedral Ward. If you seek blood
healing, and the church is willing, you should pay them a visit.

Byrgenwerth is an old place of learning. And the tomb of the gods, carved out below Yharnam,
should be familiar to every hunter. Well, once a group of young Byrgenwerth scholars
discovered a holy medium deep within the tomb. This led to the founding of the Healing Church,
and the establishment of blood healing. In this sense, everything sacred in Yharnam can be
traced back to Byrgenwerth. But today, the college lies deep within a tangled wood, abandoned
and decrepit. And furthermore, the Healing Church has declared Byrgenwerth forbidden ground.
It's unclear how many of its scholars remain alive… ...but only they know the password that
allows passage through the gate.

Ahh, there's something I want to tell you. A bit of wisdom from the eminent Master Logarius.
Once, a scholar betrayed his fellows at Byrgenwerth… …and brought forbidden blood back with
him to Cainhurst Castle. It was there that the first of the inhuman Vilebloods was born. The
Vilebloods are fiendish creatures who threaten the purity of the Church's blood healing. The
Ruler of the Vilebloods is still alive today. And so, to honor my master's wishes, I search. For the
path to Cainhurst Castle.

In his time, Master Logarius led his executioners into Cainhurst Castle to cleanse it of the
Vilebloods. But all did not go well, and Master Logarius became a blessed anchor, guarding us
from evil. ...Tragic, tragic times… that Master Logarius should be abandoned in the accursed
domain of the Vilebloods. I must free him, so that he may be properly honored in martyrdom.

Ah-hah! ls that... the sigil of Cainhurst? I've heard tell of Cainhurst nobles, and their amusingly
pompous invitations. Wonderful! I thank you profusely... I will depart immediately. But first, a
token of my gratitude.

Ahh, I feel my master's hand at work. Praise the good blood! And let us cleanse these tarnished
streets.

It has been an honor, but I must say good-bye. Let us cleanse these tarnished streets. And may
the good blood guide your way.

Master, look! I've done it, I've done it! I smashed and pounded and grounded this rotten siren
into fleshy pink pulp! There, you filthy monstrosity! What good's your immortality now! Try


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                            Script 17


stirring up trouble in this sorry state! All mangled and twisted, with every inside on the outside,
for all the world to see! He heh hah hah Hah! He heh heh ha ha haah!

Oh, you, is it? Look at this! Thanks to you, I've done it! Well? Isn't it wonderful? Now master
can be canonized as a true martyr! Ha ha ha ha ha ha! I've done it, I have!!! Hah h-hah ha ha hah!

Just what is the meaning of this? Why turn your blade on me? You're jealous! Aren't you!

Pray for Master Logarius in my stead..

A hunter's grudge is an awful thing. You must find your own way on this hunt. As I have mine.

Ha ha ha ha ha! Hah hah hah hah hah!

Unclean wench! Vile monstrosity!

Bloody fool! Has the blood gone to your head?

Pathetic! As you deserve! The blood! You've spilled my blood!

You'll... regret this...

You let the blood get the best of you... Heh heh heh...

Vicar Amelia: Seek the old blood. Let us pray, let us wish. To partake in communion. Let us
partake in communion, and feast upon the old blood. Our thirst for blood satiates us, soothes our
fears. Seek the old blood. But beware the frailty of men. Their wills are weak, minds young. The
foul beasts will dangle nectar, and lure the meek into the depths. Remain wary of the frailty of
men. Their wills are weak, minds young. Were it not for fear, death would go unlamented.

Djura: You there, hunter. Didn't you see the warning? Turn back at once. Old Yharnam, burned
and abandoned by men, is now home only to beasts. They are of no harm to those above. Turn
back… …or the hunter will face the hunt…

...You are a skilled hunter. Adept, merciless, half-cut with blood. As the best hunters are. Which
is why I must stop you!

I should think you still have dreams? Well, the next time you dream, give some thought... to the
hunt, and its purpose...



         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                             Script 18


Well, well... How did you get in here? Ah, it's no matter. What brings you to Old Yharnam? I've
no interest in matters further up, but you must not disturb this place. The beasts do not venture
above, and mean no harm to anyone. If you still insist on hunting them, then I will hunt you first.
You understand me?

Yes, very good. I no longer dream, but I was once a hunter, too. There's nothing more horrific
than a hunt. In case you've failed to realise... The things you hunt, they're not beasts. They're
people. One day, you will see... Hmm, it's time you got going... But first, a farewell gift. I have
no use for it anyway.
What is it? Surely I need not repeat myself. Go, I say. You have the whole night to dream. Make
the best of it.

Of course, I thought as much. You are a true hunter. Which is why I must stop you!

You devious rat! The makings of a true hunter, this fellow/lass! Very well. Then there's no need
to hold back! The beasts will feast tonight!

Is it the blood, or are you just raving mad?

When the frail of heart joins the fray... The hunter becomes the hunted!

Then come as often as you like, and I will show you another death.

...lt's you... you're the beast... Just think about what you're doing. It's utter madness…

Gascoigne’s Younger Daughter: Who... are you? I don't know your voice, but I know that
smell... Are you a hunter? Then, please, will you look for my mum? Daddy never came back
from the hunt, an d she went to find him, but now she's gone, too... I'm all alone... and scared...

Really? Oh, thank you! My m-mum wears a red jeweled brooch. It's so big and... a nd beautiful.
You won't miss it. Oh, I mustn't forget. If you find my mum, give her this music box. ...It plays
one of daddy's favorite songs. And when daddy forgets us we play it for him so he remembers.
Mum's so silly, running off without it!

Oh, alright... Well th-thanks mister/miss hunter, for talking, at least. Take care, on your hunt.

Thanks for chatting. Please be careful out there! Hello, [mister/miss] hunter. Still can't find my
mum?




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                            Script 19


Yes, okay. I can wait. Mum knows I'm really brave, and you're very kind. I won't be afraid, I'll
be a good girl, I promise.

Oh, okay. I can wait. But isn't there something I can do? Maybe mum and dad are stuck out
there… …waiting for me to come and find them. What do you think, mister/miss hunter?

Yes, okay! Thank you, mister/miss hunter. I love you almost as much as mum and dad, and
granddad!

Yes, I see... I can wait. I won't be afraid. I know, I do. The morning always comes.

Mum, come home... I'm alone... I'm scared... It's not fair...

Mister/Miss hunter... was it really her? ...Mummy... mummy... Don't leave me alone...

Gascoigne’s Eldest Daughter: Oh, you haven't by any chance... seen my little sister, have you?
I told her to look after the house, but she's run off somewhere. She's still quite small, and wears a
big white ribbon. Have you seen her out there anywhere?

Oh, how did this happen... Why would she ever go outside? At least... I'll have something to
remember her by.

What a perfect ribbon... And now it's mine... I can't wait to try it on...

Oh, it's wonderful...

Oh, okay then. But if you do see her, would you give me word? She's a small girl, with a big
white ribbon. My good little sister...

Oh, back again? Any news of my sister?

Gatekeeper: The password... The password...

...password... Got to close the... Ahh, ahh, ohhhhh....

Patches: Oh, a hunter of beasts, are you? Glory be. You know not the value you possess. But,
more's the pity... The hours of the night are many, and the beasts more than I can count. A
veritable hunt unending! Not even death offers solace, and the blood imbibes you.




         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                             Script 20


Ha, a most frightful fate, oh my. But I'm willing to do you a kindness. Step lightly round to the
right of the great cathedral, and seek an ancient, shrouded church. The gift of the godhead will
grant you strength... Yes, I'm unquestionably certain, heheh…

Oh Amygdala, oh Amygdala... Have mercy on the poor bastard...

What a joy it is, to behold the divine. It must be such a pleasure. You're in my debt, you know.
You're nigh on a beast of the field, but here you are, treading a measure with the gods. Are your
feet as fat as your Wits? Oh, cease this dithering! Take the plunge! Throw yourself to the
wolves!

Don't dally, you lucky scamp! The gift of the godhead cometh! Oh, this cannot be, you cannot
be... No, you didn't... lord Amygdala… ...How did this come to pass?

Hmph! Now, wait just a moment... Do you think ill of me, me?

Oh, it pains me to hear it. You've made yourself a misreckoning. I shared with you a thing most
secret. Now you're witness to a miracle, and all the stronger for it! It‘s plain as a pikestaff. Now,
say in my heart, you were as a lamb to my god. Well, you weren't to know, and it wasn't for you
to know. All's well, that ends well, I say.

You should appreciate it, if you’ve a grain of gratitude in you! Appreciate it!

No matter. Such details are trifling. We're fast friends by now. Let this express what words
cannot.

Oh, doubt me not, sweet compeer. What is friendship, but a chance encounter?

Ahh, well met. My apologies, but I feel a profound thought occurring... On the good grace of a
certain god, and the way he meted out his love.

Ahh, well met. This is a most pleasing encounter. You see, I must depart erelong. My god is lost
to me, so I must go away to find another. If the fates are kind, our paths may cross again. Sooner
still... if you were you to take the leap...

Ahh, well met. Oh, think not of poor Amygdala. Upon that piteous bastard, you bestowed
salvation. All‘s well that ends well.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                           Script 21


Aah! The sight of you is as balm to my eyes! Truly, you are an indubitable, irrefutable friend!
And, my dear compeer, I vow once more to ease your burden! Truly, you are an indubitable,
irrefutable friend!

The time has come again I fear. But if the fates smile upon us, we'll soon meet again. Farewell,
dear friend. Farewell, dear friend.

Ergh, that was uncharitably done... That was uncharitably done, dear friend…

Micolash, Host of the Nightmare: Ooh! Majestic! A hunter is a hunter, even in a dream. But,
alas, not too fast! The nightmare swirls and churns unending!

Ahh, Kos, or some say Kosm... Do you hear our prayers? As you once did for the vacuous Rom,
Grant us eyes, grant us eyes. Plant eyes on our brains, to cleanse our beastly idiocy.

The grand lake of mud, hidden now, from sight. The cosmos, of course

Let us sit about, and speak feverishly. Chatting into the wee hours of... New ideas, of the higher
plane!

Now I'm waking up, I'll forget everything…

Ahh, Kos, or some say Kosm... Do you hear our prayers? No, we shall not abandon the dream.
No one can catch us! No one can stop us now!

Provost Willem: Oh, I know, I know. You think now, to betray me. ...The blood makes us
human, makes us more than human, makes us human no more. Our eyes are yet to open...

By the gods, fear it, Laurence.

Laurence: Master Willem, I've come to bid you farewell.

No, but you will never listen. I tell you, I will not forget our adage.

Fear the old blood.

I must take my leave.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                          Script 22


Annalise, Queen of the Vilebloods: Visitor... I claim no subjects, but here lieth Our throne.
Kneel afore Us… or get thee gone.

Visitor... Moon-scented hunter... I am Annalise, Queen of Castle Cainhurst. Ruler of the
Vilebloods, and sworn enemy of the church. Yet, Our people are murdered, and We are prisoner
to this wretched mask. What is it thou'rt in search of?

Visitor... Moon-scented hunter... Speak thy mind.

Well, well... An odd hunter thou art indeed... We've tired of these piteous nights... Share in Our
plight, and take oath against the church. If thou wouldst this path walk… l prithee partake of my
rotted blood.

An odd hunter thou art indeed... Very well. Drink deep of Our blood. Feel the spreading
corruption burn. Now, thou'rt too a Vileblood. We two, the very last on this earth.

A wise choice... There is no more to be said. Away from mine gaze.

Such impudence. Defiled, are We, yet still Queen. We shall not give audience to an ill-mannered
beast. We shall not give audience to an ill-mannered beast. Get thee gone.

Closest of kin, bearer of Our blood. I welcome thee. What is thy wish?

Closest of kin, last of Our kind. I welcome thee. What is thy wish?

More talk to be had?

Thy gift pleases Us. Let this reward be thine. Indulge thyself in Our tainted blood.

Speak not, those words. We have little need of a consort. Such a path would belike lead to
further ruin. Thou'rt dear to Us. We would see no harm befall thee...

Ahh, still thy honeyed tongue... The thought alone sufficeth. Thy worth is too great. Now, speak
no more on the matter.

Honestly!

Arrant fool. Vileblood or no, forget not; We are thy Queen. Bend the knee.

Vileblood or no, respect will be shown.


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                            Script 23


We await thy return. For the honor of Cainhurst.

We await thy return. ...This chamber was made not for one alone...

How sad this is. If only Our life was so easily forfeit...

Art thou brave, or merely lacking in wit? It matters not. Our flesh is undying. Speak thy mind.

Well, well. Thou wearest a second face. It matters not. Our flesh is undying. Speak thy mind.

Valtr, Master of the League: Ahh, a new face, are you? And an accomplished hunter... it would
appear. I am Valtr, Master of the League. Members of the League cleanse the streets of all the
filth that's spread about during the hunt. Like any half-decent hunter ought to, you know?

Haven't you seen enough of these wretched beasts, freakish slugs, and mad doctors?

Sentence these fiends to death. With the help of your League confederates. What do you say?
Why not join the League?

Yes. As a hunter well should. Commit this to heart. Our own Caryll rune, symbol of the League.
The nights brims with defiled scum, and is permeated by their rotten stench. Just think. Now
you're all set to hunt and kill to your heart's content. Hunt in co-operation with your fellows, your
League confederates.

Yes, I suppose... I should not force your will. But you are a hunter, and will see soon enough.

That on a night of the hunt, no, on any night, nothing out there deserves to live.

Well, then? Seen enough out there? Fancy joining the ranks of the League?

Now, there is one thing you must know. By the oath of the League, those who bear its rune will
see vermin. Vermin writhe deep within all filth, and are the root of man's impurity. ...All vermin
are to be crushed. The League exists to expunge all vermin, ridding us of any trace of human
corruption. And so, until we are rid of all vermin, you must continue to hunt and kill. This
bloody fate is ours alone. Do not expect the world to grasp our work... But remember, the
confederates will always have my blessing... And each other. Always.

Ahh, how goes your hunt? Do not forget the League's mission. To co-operate with confederates,
find vermin, and stamp them out.



         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                               Script 24


Ahh, very good. You've crushed some vermin. I am the Master of the League, I can see it in your
eyes. I'm pleased. This makes you a true fellow of the League. ...A confederate. Now, take this
staff. A symbol of our oath, of our blood-drenched fate. You'll be welcomed as a true
confederate. Go forth, with renewed vigor. ...In short time, you will see... How the mission takes
hold of one's spirits.

Hello, confederate. Has your stomach not turned? Turned at the world of man, so wondrously
wretched! And brimming with unsightly vermin. Much like our very own mission.

Hello, confederate. Your eyes say it all. You've crushed vermin time and time again... You've
seen the filth that varnishes the world of man... Yet you are unbroken, you've the eyes of a
hunter. You have blessed the League with your presence. This was my last, most pressing task...

My confederate. Promise me you'll crush all vermin, to rid us of our impurities. For the sake of
our fellows, all blood-stained hunters of the League. My confederate. Promise me you'll crush all
vermin, to rid us of our impurities.

Well, how quaint. You scoff at the League? Then you are yourself a beast. A defiled mess of
rotten flesh!

When you are dead, your rank blood will curdle with vermin!

Look, look, I knew it! Vermin writhe and squirm... You vile lout.

My time is done... Glory to my League confederates…

Suspicious Beggar: Blimey, don't scare me like that! On a night like this... I took you for a
monster. Oh, thank the stars, you're fairly normal... Was it you put down that awful beast? Oh,
that thing had me trembling, frozen in me boots. And then you came along. Well, if you're a
hunter... then... would you know of any safe havens?

Well, I'll be! Thank you! It's about time I made a move. I can't very well stay out on me own...

Oh, you've given me hope... Terribly kind of you. Take this. It's all I can offer as thanks.

Oh yeah, of course not... I should've known. This whole place's falling apart, once again... It's the
curse of Yharnam...

Thank you. It's about time I made a move. I can't very well stay out on me own... Oh, you again!



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                               Script 25


You find any nice, cozy places to hole up in? You find any nice, cozy places to hole up in?

Ah, hello again. I owe this to you. It's a wonderful place. They even let beggars like meself in!
What's better... we keep our distance, don't step on anyone's toes, right? The way proper
Yharnamites ought to live! Oh, let me share something with you. My secret stash. Really prime
stuff...

Oh, hello again. I really do owe you a terrible lot. Finding me such a nice place to Iive...

Oh, hi. I'm afraid I don't have any more. Yeah, it's all sold out. Sorry, chum. But, you know... I'll
try and get some more soon. But, you know it ain't easy, right? Yeah, it's all sold out. Sorry,
chum.

Oh, you again. Perfect timing. I've got some more. See? Oh, oh my... you just can‘t get enough.
Oh no, I understand, I'm the very same. This is a smashing place. It‘s everything Yharnam ever
had, and more!

Have you got a screw loose? Or is it your... animal intuition? Oh, it doesn't even matter. You
hunters've got more blood on your hands! Oh, you are a sick puppy! You drink the blood of half
the town, and now this! And you talk of beasts? You hunters are the real killers!

Oh, you are a sick puppy!

Die! Die, die! Hunters are killers, nothing less! You call me a beast? A beast? What would you
know? I didn't ask for this! You're no different than I. Rancid beasts, every last one of us…

Bloody Corpse: Ahh, ahh, please… help us… Ah… An unsightly beast… a great terror looms!
Ahh! Ludwig the Accursed is coming! Have mercy! Have mercy upon us!

Ludwig, the Holy Blade: Aah, you were at my side, all along. My true mentor... My guiding
moonlight...

Good hunter, have you seen the thread of light? Just a hair, a fleeting thing, yet I clung to it,
steeped as I was in the stench of blood and beasts. I never wanted to know, what it really was.
Really, I didn't.

Tell me, good hunter of the Church. Have you seen the light? Are my Church hunters the
honorable spartans I hoped they would be?




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                           Script 26


Ahh, good... that is a relief. To know I did not suffer such denigration for nothing. Thank you
kindly. Now I may sleep in peace. Even in this darkest of nights, I see... the moonlight...

Oh, my. Just as I feared. Then a beast-possessed degenerate was I, as my detractors made
eminently clear. Does the nightmare never end?!

Yamamura: Shrouded by night, but with steady stride. Colored by blood, but always clear of
mind. Proud hunter of the Church.

Beasts are a curse, and a curse is a shackle. Only ye are the true blades of the Church.

Simon the Harrowed: You're a hunter with your sanity, aren't you? Must've taken a wrong turn
then, eh? Well, we're more alike than you think. This is the Hunter's Nightmare, where hunters
end up when drunk with blood. You've seen them before. Aimless, wandering hunters, slavering
like beasts. This is what the poor fools have to look forward to. So, don't be brash, turn back
before it's too late. Unless, you've something of an interest in nightmares?

Ahh, yes, I see... You sense a secret within the Nightmare, and cannot bear to leave it be. As if
the spirit of Byrgenwerth lives on within you! Such inquisitive hunters will relish the Nightmare.
If anyone deserves to have this, it is you. But beware, secrets are secrets for a reason. And some
do not wish to see them uncovered. Especially when the secrets are particularly unseemly...

Yes, as it should be. Hunt your beasts, and think no more on the secrets of the night. That is the
very best a hunter can do. Just don't let the blood intoxicate you.

What now? Take my word, and turn back before it's too late. Unless, I suppose, you've taken an
interest in nightmares?

Oh, he's well and truly gone, now. A tragic figure. But he will shame himself no longer. He died
with his ideals untarnished. He was a true hero, and earnt that much, at least.

Here, this is Ludwig's guiding light. The blinding thread that led, and misled, that consummate
hero. The poor brute.

A tragic figure. But he will shame himself no longer. He died with his ideals untarnished. He was
a true hero, and earnt that much, at least.

Do you know why the Hunters are drawn to this Nightmare? Because it sprouted from their very
misdeeds. Things that some would rather keep secret. A pitiful tale of petty arrogance, really.
High time someone exposed the whole charade.


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                                 Script 27



Now, now, go on ahead. You seek nightmares, and the secrets within, do you not?
Oh, hello. Not a pretty sight, is it? The true face of the blood-worshipping, beast-purging Healing
Church. But that's not all. You seek the secrets held by the Nightmare, do you not? Then here's
what you must do. ...Climb the Astral Clocktower, and kill Maria. She hides the real secret...

Go on, kill Maria atop the Astral Clocktower. She hides the real secret...

...Oh, you, I'm afraid, I've made a botch of things... ...I can hear the bell, now... ...The beast-hide
assassin, he's after me... ...Again and again... ...It never ends...

...Please, I need you to do something... ...This village is the true secret. Testament to the old
sins... ...It feeds this Hunter's Nightmare... ...Please, bring to an end the horror...

...So our forefathers sinned? ...We hunters cannot bear their weight forever... ...It isn't fair, it just
isn't fair...

Tsk! Taken by the Nightmare, are you? Then I've no choice. Prepare yourself!

Terribly sorry, but I couldn't let you stop me...

Curses. What a rotten place to die...

Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower: Oh, I know very well, how the secrets beckon so
sweetly. Only an honest death will cure you now. Liberate you, from your wild curiosity.

Brador, Church Assassin: Are you a hunter? Well, that's very odd. Do you hear the toll of the
bell?

Hmph. Liar. Such pettiness will be your undoing. The beasts you seek will not be found here. Go
back to your hunt, and if you have the chance, put this night behind you. ...places better left
untouched, secrets better left alone... ...only a fool would so brazenly roam...

Very well. The beasts you seek will not be found here. Go back to your hunt, and if you have the
chance, put this night behind you. ...places better left untouched, secrets better left alone... ...only
a fool would so brazenly roam...

Bear in mind. Some places are better left untouched, and some secrets are better left
alone. ...only fools do brazenly roam...



         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                             Script 28


Do you hear this? Fear the bell's toll. For only death awaits foolish prying eyes, and the Church
assassins are never far behind.

Well, well, look who's here. Welcome to my quarters. I've never entertained a guest before. Are
you going to kill me? After all you've done, kill me, as if to right your wrongs?

What is it? Aren't you going to kill me? Or perhaps, beg my forgiveness? Well, leave off. What's
done is done.

Nothing changes, such is the nature of men...

...unending death awaits those who pry into the unknown...

Fishing Hamlet Priest: Byrgenwerth... Byrgenwerth... Blasphemous murderers... Blood-crazed
fiends... Atonement for the wretches... By the wrath of Mother Kos... Mercy for the poor,
wizened child... Mercy, oh please...

Atonement for the wretches... Lay the curse of blood upon them, and their children, and their
children's children, for evermore. Each wretched birth will plunge each child into a lifetime of
misery.

Mercy for the poor, wizened child... Let the pungence of Kos cling, like a mother's devotion...

Curse here, curse there. A curse for he, and she, why care. A bottomless curse, a bottomless sea,
source of all greatness, all things that be. Listen for the baneful chants. Weep with them, as one
in trance. And weep with us, oh, weep with us...
A call to the bloodless, wherever they be. A call to the bloodless, wherever they be. Fix your
ears, to hear our calls.

...Ahh, sweet child of Kos, returned to the ocean... A bottomless curse, a bottomless sea.
Accepting of all that there is and can be.

Plain Doll: Ahh, you've found yourself a hunter...

Hello, good hunter. I am a doll, here in this dream to look after you. Honorable hunter, pursue
the echoes of blood, and I will channel them into your strength. You will hunt beasts... and I will
be here for you, to embolden your sickly spirit.

Welcome home, good hunter. What is it you desire?



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                              Script 29


Welcome home, good hunter. Very well, let the echoes become your strength. Let me stand
close. Now shut your eyes...

Farewell, good hunter. May you find your worth in the waking world.

Did you speak with Gehrman? He was a hunter long, long ago, but now serves only to advise
them. He is obscure, unseen in the dreaming world. Still, he stays here, in this dream… ...such is
his purpose...

Ahh, the little ones, inhabitants of the dream... They find hunters like yourself, worship, and
serve them. Speak words, they do not, but still, aren't they sweet?

Over time, countless hunters have visited this dream. The graves here stand in their memory. It
all seems so long ago now...

Hunters have told me about the church. About the gods, and their love. But... do the gods love
their creations? I am a doll, created by you humans. Would you ever think to love me? Of
course... I do love you. Isn't that how you've made me?

Good hunter... Your presence somehow soothes... I sense the ancient echoes, they course your
veins...

What... what is this? I-I can't remember, not a thing, only... I feel... A yearning... something I've
never felt before... What's happening to me? Ahh... Tell me hunter, could this be joy?
Good hunter, you have come... Dawn will soon break... This night, and this dream, will end.
Gehrman awaits you, at the foot of the great tree. Go on, good hunter...

Farewell, good hunter. May you find your worth in the waking world.

And so, the hunt begins again.

Are you cold...? Oh, good hunter.

O Flora, of the moon, of the dream. O little ones, O fleeting will of the ancients... Let the hunter
be safe, let him/her find comfort. And let this dream, his/her captor… foretell a pleasant
awakening… be, one day, a fond, distant memory...

Welcome home, good hunter. I must have drifted off... What is it you desire?




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                            Script 30


Ahh, welcome home, good hunter. That I may channel into your strength. Very well, let the
echoes of blood become your strength.

Good hunter. This may sound strange, but... Have I somehow changed? Moments ago, from
some place, perhaps deep within, I sensed a liberation from heavy shackles.

Not that I would know... How passing strange...

Oh, good hunter. I can hear Gehrman sleeping. On any other night, he'd be restless. But on this
night, he sounds so very calm. ...Perhaps something has eased his suffering.

Gehrman, The First Hunter: Ah-hah, you must be the new hunter. Welcome to the Hunter's
Dream. This will be your home, for now. I am... Gehrman, friend to you hunters. You're sure to
be in a fine haze about now, but don't think too hard about all of this. Just go out and kill a few
beasts. It's for your own good. You know, it's just what hunters do! You'll get used to it...

This was once a safe haven for hunters. A workshop where hunters used blood to enhance their
weapons and flesh. We don't have as many tools as we once did, but... You're welcome to use
whatever you find. ...Even the doll, should it please you...

The moon is close. It will be a long hunt tonight. If the beasts loom large, and threaten to crush
your spirits, seek a Holy Chalice. As every hunter before you has. A Holy Chalice will reveal the
tomb of the gods, ...where hunters partake in communion...

Oh, Laurence... what's taking you so long... I've grown too old for this, of little use now, I'm
afraid...

Most of the Holy Chalices lie deep within the tomb of the gods. And the few that found their way
to the surface... Were lost again in the hands of men. But if the old hunter tales remain true…
one of the Holy Chalices is worshipped in the valley hamlet. Yet the town is in disarray... It was
burned and abandoned, for fear of the scourge, home now only to beasts. The perfect place for a
hunter, wouldn't you say?

One of the Holy Chalices is worshipped in the valley hamlet. A town of beasts... the perfect
place for a hunter...

The Healing Church, and the Blood Ministers who belong to it... Were once guardians of the
hunters, in the times of the hunter... Ludwig. They worked, and forged weapons, in their unique
workshop. Today, most ministers don't recall the hunters. But they have much to offer you. And
so, heed the message of your forebears. Ascend to Oedon Chapel.


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                            Script 31


Ascend to Oedon Chapel. From there, you will find the church workshop.

...Oh, Laurence... Master Willem... Somebody, help me... Unshackle me, please, anybody... I've
had enough of this dream... The night blocks all sight... Oh, somebody, please...

Good hunter, you've done well. The night is near its end. Now, I will show you mercy. You will
die, forget the dream, and awake under the morning sun. You will be freed… from this terrible
hunter's dream... Farewell, my keen hunter. Fear the blood.

Dear oh dear, what was it? The hunt, the blood, or the horrible dream? Oh, it doesn't matter. It
always comes down to the hunters’ helper to clean up after these sorts of messes. Tonight,
Gehrman joins the hunt...

The night, and the dream, were long...

You must accept your death. Be freed from the night…

Yharnamites: Lousy offcomer. Who'd open their door on a night of the hunt! Away with you.
Now!

Are you that outsider? Well, sorry, but I don't want anything to do with ya. Trot along, willya.


Praise you... praise the whole damn church... And best of luck hunting, best luck of all!

...Bless us with blood… ...Bless us with blood...

A night of curses, a night to remember! Wouldn't you say, friend?

Help me... Please help...

Ahhhh! Stop! You stop right there! Not an inch closer!

A celebration, a great night of celebration!
Wretched outsider! Tryin' to fool me to open this door? Heavens, the depths of depravity...

I don't reckon you're from ‘round here! Well, pffft, stuck outside on a night of the hunt! Ahh, you
poor, poor thing...




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                               Script 32


Ahh, ohh... Oh, we've the deepest gratitude! For the church, and all they do for us. The deepest,
widest, gratitude, yes!

…Oh, heavens... would you stop that? Every peep you make brings us bad luck! I have it bad
enough already...Please, just leave a poor old woman be...

Do you hear the graveyard murmurs? Then it's almost time. Oh, I can't wait. I just can't wait!

Oh! Ah! My baby! My precious, little baby! Stay away, stay away from us!

Research Hall Patients: ...Kill me... please, just kill me... Free me from this place... before I go
mad.

Ahh, Lady Maria, Lady Maria. Please. Take my hand. Please. Help me... don't let me drown...

Has someone, anyone, seen my eyes? I'm afraid I've dropped them in a puddle. Everything is
pale, now...

Listen close... and you, too, will hear... The sound of water... Splish, splash, splish, splash... Plip,
plop, plip, plop...

Ahh, someone... help me... I am guilty, I know. But I won't do it again, I promise. The damp
darkness... it, it frightens me... And what rises from its very depths...
Oh, Lady Maria... Save me... please... I don't hear anything... I have failed. Please, Lady Maria...

Lady Maria, I'm a robin. Will I ever curl up and become an egg? What say you, Lady Maria?
Lady Maria? Say something, anything...

Have you heard how curiously the sea churns? Like a storm, but like the rain, only gentle, like
dripping water... It bellows, from deep inside of me... Here it comes, up through my insides...
But gently, like little droplets... Splish, splash, splish, splash... Plip, plop, plip, plop...

Lady Maria, I'm a robin. Will I ever curl up and become an egg? What say you, Lady Maria?
Lady Maria? Say something, anything...

Have you heard how curiously the sea churns? Like a storm, but like the rain, only gentle, like
dripping water... It bellows, from deep inside of me... Here it comes, up through my insides...
But gently, like little droplets... Splish, splash, splish, splash... Plip, plop, plip, plop...




         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                    Script 33


Baneful Chanters: Mother is dead, her baby, taken.

Scales are suffering, the grief of Kos.

Do you hear it? A sealess void, the lair of beasts. Where the blood-crazed roam.
Do you hear the sealess void? The lair of beasts, the blood-mad roam.

Curse the fiends, their children too. And their children, forever, true.

Kos we have beckoned, and Kos is dead. Forgive us, and curses upon the fiends.

Kos we beckoned, dear Kos, no more. Forgiveness upon us, curse the fiends.

Enemy Yharnamites: Die!

Cursed beast!

Vile beast!

Please, God!

You plague-ridden rat!

Beast! A foul beast!

You fiend!

You are not wanted here!

It's all your fault!

I'll mash up your brain!

Help me! Oh, God!

Away! Away!

This... This stench... Smells like you, stranger.

Oh, this curse. This is a damned curse.


         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 34


We all know who's at fault. We know precisely who it is.

We're finished.

There's no... hope.

We're cursed. We're all cursed.

Please, God, help me. I must live.

Oh, bugger! Where'd the beast go?

Damn! Where you hidin’?

Dammit! Where are you tryin’ to go?

You foul beast! You can’t hide for long!

Over here! The outsider!

Found you!

Burn! Burn!

Idola will be the judge!

Rip the kid apart!

Death to the minister! Death!

Kill! Yes!

This town's finished.

You are cursed, foul beast.

You won't last long. Death to all cursed beasts. Death upon you.

Please, God.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                    Script 35


Kill! Kill!

Die! Ha ha ha!

Die, you rat!

We're a-hunting! Cleanse this curse upon ye!

Bloood! The streets will run red!

Busybody! Leave us be!

A mess of ash you'll be!

Cleanse this cursed filth!

Damned beast! Go on, be merry... and mad.

You'll pay for this.

You're better off dead!

It's your fault.

So cold... Dear sister...

Where are you!?


                               Item Descriptions

Weapons:
Hunter Axe: One of the trick weapons of the workshop, commonly
used by those who dedicate themselves to the hunt.

Retains the qualities of an axe, but offers wider
palette of attacks by transforming. Boasts a heavy


         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                    Script 36


blunt attack, leading to high rally potential.

No matter their pasts, beasts are no more than beasts.
Some choose this axe to play the part of executioner.

Saw Cleaver: One of the trick weapons of the workshop, commonly
used in the hunting business.

This saw, effective at drawing the blood of beasts,
transforms into a long cleaver that makes use of
centrifugal force.

The saw, with its set of blood-letting teeth, has become
a symbol of the hunt, and only grows in effectiveness
the more grotesquely transformed the beast.

Saw Spear: One of the trick weapons of the workshop, commonly
used by those who dedicate themselves to the hunt.

This saw, effective at drawing the blood of beasts,
transforms into a medium-range spear.

The saw, with its set of blood-letting teeth, has become
a symbol of the hunt, and only grows in effectiveness
the more grotesquely transformed the beast.

Threaded Cane: One of the trick weapons of the workshop, commonly used
by hunters on their duties.

Sufficiently deadly as a rigid bladed cane, but also serves as
a whip when its blade is split into many.

Concealing the weapon inside the cane and flogging the
beasts with the whip is partly an act of ceremony, an
attempt to demonstrate to oneself that the bloodlust of the
hunt will never encroach upon the soul.

Kirkhammer: A trick weapon typically used by Healing Church hunters.

On the one side, an easily handled silver sword.


         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                        Script 37


On the other, a giant obtuse stone weapon, characterized
by a blunt strike and extreme force of impact.

The Church takes a heavy-handed, merciless stance
toward the plague of beasts, an irony not lost upon the wielders of this most symbolic weapon.

Rifle Spear: A trick weapon crafted by the workshop heretics, the Powder Kegs.

A prototype weapon serving as a simple firearm and
spear, possibly created in imitation of a lost Cainhurst weapon.

Lacks any notable functions, saving that it is the only
trick weapon with an attached gun.

Stake Driver: A trick weapon fashioned by the workshop heretics,
the Powder Kegs. Favored by the retired hunter Djura.

The stake driver, with its queerly complex design, violently
drives thick stakes into the flesh of foes.

The stake driver allows for high-damage critical attacks, but
is difficult to use and leaves its wielder wide open, but none
of this should bother a mere Powder Keg.

Ludwig’s Holy Blade: A trick weapon typically used by Healing Church hunters.

It is said that the silver sword was employed by Ludwig,
the first hunter of the church. When transformed,
it combines with its sheath to form a greatsword.

It exhibits several departures from the workshop's
design, suggesting that the Church anticipated
much larger inhuman beasts.

Blade of Mercy: A special trick weapon passed down among
hunters of hunters. One of the oldest weapons
of the workshop.

Splits into two when activated. The weapon's
warped blades are forged with siderite, a rare mineral


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 38


of the heavens. Most effective swift attacks,
such as after a quick-stepping.

Tonitrus: A unique trick weapon contrived by Archibald, the infamous
eccentric of the Healing Church workshop.

Striking this peculiar iron morning star flail like a match
generates the same blue sparks that blanket a darkbeast.

Unfortunately, for reasons untold, the hunters of Archibald's
time did not fully take to the device.

Chikage: Foreign-made weapon wielded by the royal guards who
protect Annalise, Queen of the Vilebloods at Cainhurst
Castle.

When the intricate, rippled engraving that spans the
Chikage's blade is imbrued with blood, the sword sings in
scarlet hues.

However, the rite eats away at the wielder's very essence.

Reiterpallash: Weapon wielded by the Knights of Cainhurst.

Combines an elegant knight's sword with the peculiar
firearm wielded by the Cainhurst order.

The old nobles, long-time imbibers of blood, are no strangers
to the sanguine plague,and the disposal of beasts was a
discrete task left to their servants, or knights, as they were
called for the sake of appearances.

Logarius’ Wheel: Weapon wielded by martyr Logarius' band of executioners.

Used to slaughter the Vilebloods in Cainhurst. Bathed in
pools of their blood, and forever steeped in their ire.

Transform to release the power of the wheel and manifest
their lingering rage in a show of utter brilliance.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 39


Burial Blade: Trick weapon wielded by Gehrman, the first hunter.

A masterpiece that defined the entire array of weapons
crafted at the workshop. Its blade is forged with siderite,
said to have fallen from the heavens.

Gehrman surely saw the hunt as a dirge of farewell, wishing
only that his prey might rest in peace, never again to awaken
to another harrowing nightmare.

Beast Claw: Beastly weapon wielded by Irreverent Izzy.

Crafted by chiseling the long bones of an undead darkbeast
and fastening them to the weapon. The bones are still alive,
and when unleashed, grant its wielder a spurt of beastly
power.

As flesh is flayed and blood is sprayed, the beast within
awakens, and in time, the wielder of this weapon surges with
both strength and feverish reverie.

Amygdalan Arm: The arm of a small Amygdala Great One.

Strictly speaking, the Amygdalan Arm is no trick weapon of
any sort, but certain madmen wield them like clubs.

Starts as a large, tough blunt weapon formed of bone, but
when extended, the arm quivers as if it were still alive.

Beasthunter Saif: A trick weapon used by the old hunters.

A second blade is found inside the curve of the main one. In
its initial form, the saif can be wielded like a long curved
sword, but when transformed, its blade is contracted,
allowing for quick, repeated stabs.

Although this trick weapon allows for adaptive combat, it
was later replaced by saws and similar weapons that were
more effective at disposing of beasts.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 40


Beast Cutter: A trick weapon wielded by the old hunters.

This thick iron cleaver slices through the toughest of beast
hides, and when transformed the blade splits into sections,
allowing one to lash it in the fashion of a heavy whip.

The crude weapon relies on brute force and is regrettably
inelegant, suggesting that the hunts of the earliest hunters
made for horrific affairs, painted in sanguine blacks and
reds.

Bloodletter: The demented hunter weapon brandished by Brador,
the Healing Church assassin.

The Bloodletter assumes its true and terrifying form after it
draws upon blood from the inner reaches of one's body and
soul.

This is the only effective means of expelling tainted blood, or
so Brador, isolated in his cell, continued to believe.

Boom Hammer: A trick weapon used by the old hunters, and crafted by the
workshop heretics, the Powder Kegs.

A giant hammer equipped with a miniature furnace. When
ignited and fired, it emits a volley of flame that explodes
furiously upon impact.

Crush the beasts, then burn them - the brute simplicity of the
Boom Hammer was favored by hunters with an acute
distaste for beasts.

Church Pick: One of the old trick weapons of the Healing Church, a
hunting weapon formed from one of the giant picks that
appears in the old beast tales.

The Church Pick initially serves as a large sword, but when
transformed, functions as an extended war pick. In spite of
its origins, it is a highly practical weapon.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 41


Holy Moonlight Sword: An arcane sword discovered long ago by Ludwig.
When blue moonlight dances around the sword, and it
channels the abyssal cosmos, its great blade will hurl a shadowy lightwave.
The Holy Moonlight Sword is synonymous with Ludwig, the
Holy Blade, but few have ever set eyes on the great blade,
and whatever guidance it has to offer, it seems to be of a
very private, elusive sort.

Kos Parasite: When the carcass of Kos washed up on the coast, its insides
were teeming with tiny parasites, unlike any found in
humans.

This atypical weapon can only be clasped tight and swung,
but a Kos Parasite is said to stimulate phantasms inhabiting
a lumenwood.

Rakuyo: Hunter weapon wielded by Lady Maria of the Astral
Clocktower.

A trick sword originated in the same country as the
Cainhurst Chikage, only this sword feeds not off blood, but
instead demands great dexterity.

Lady Maria was fond of this aspect of the Rakuyo, as she
frowned upon blood blades, despite being a distant relative
of the queen.

One day, she abandoned her beloved Rakuyo, casting it into
a dark well, when she could stomach it no longer.

Simon’s Bowblade: Choice weapon of Simon, one of the first Healing Church
hunters.

Simon despised firearms, and so the Church workshop had
this specially fashioned to his liking. The large curved blade
serves as a bow when transformed.

But aside from a few close friends, Simon was scoffed at for
his choice of arms, for who would dare face the beasts with
a measly bow?


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 42


Whirligig Saw: A trick weapon crafted by the workshop heretics, the
Powder Kegs, and weapon of choice for the old hunter Valtr,
the Beast Eater.

This weapon pummels beasts in its mace form, but its true
strength lies in its attached mechanical saws.
These discs, lined with serrated teeth, spin rapidly, trashing
the flesh of beasts into fine shreds.

Hunter Blunderbuss: A blunderbuss created at the workshop for the hunters'
line of work.

Hunter firearms are specially crafted to employ Quicksilver
Bullets fused with the wielder's own blood, boosting damage
against beasts.

The impact of this highly-effective weapon counters beasts'
swift movements, and its wide spread is nigh-on guaranteed
to hit the mark.

Hunter Pistol: Pistol made at the workshop, for hunters stalking beasts.

Hunter firearms are specially crafted to employ
Quicksilver Bullets fused with the wielder's own blood,
boosting damage against beasts.

The pistol is a quicker draw than the blunderbuss,
allowing for speedier responses to attacks.

Flamesprayer: A special weapon used by certain members of the Healing
Church.
Spits searing flames by using blood-imbued Quicksilver
Bullets as a special medium.

Not the most efficient weapon by any stretch, but sometimes
a sea of flame is just what the doctor ordered.

Besides, the beasts of Yharnam can always use a good
cleansing.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 43


Repeating Pistol: Repeating pistol typically used by Healing Church hunters.

Crafted with mostly metal parts and exhibiting a complex design,
the repeating pistol fires two shots at once,
making it a ravenous consumer of Quicksilver Bullets.

Should be used sparingly compared to its workshop counterpart,
as the trump card in one's arsenal.

Cannon: Large prototype firearms fashioned by the workshop
heretics, the Powder Kegs.

Use of this weapon is equivalent to toting a mounted
cannon, complete with its ridiculous weight, staggering
kick, and lavish use of Quicksilver Bullets, into battle.

Such a monstrosity was doomed from the start, and
indeed its development was cut short. Yet, against
impossibly gigantic foes, it might be just the thing.

Ludwig’s Rifle: A rifle typically used by Healing Church hunters.

It is said that this rifle was employed by Ludwig,
the first hunter of the Church. Its long, heavy barrel
makes up in range for what it lacks in reload speed.

Ludwig's Rifle exhibits several departures from the
workshop's design, suggesting that the Church
anticipated much larger inhuman beasts.

Evelyn: Special pistol used by Cainhurst knights.

The Evelyn uses Quicksilver Bullets, just as any workshop
firearm, but the Cainhurst variant relies more on bloodtinge.

Lovingly named after a woman and graced with an intricate
design, Evelyns were adored by Cainhurst knights.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 44


Rosmarinus: A special weapon used by the Choir, high-ranking
members of the Healing Church.

Sprays a cloud of sacred mist, created by using
blood-imbued Quicksilver Bullets as a special medium.

Arias are heard wherever sacred mist is seen, proving
that the mist is a heavenly blessing.

"Oh, fair maiden, why is it that you weep?"

Church Cannon: An oversized weapon used by the Healing Church. a type of
cannon that fires with a curved trajectory and creates an
explosion upon impact.

Originally designed for use by brawny men with deteriorated
brains, not for just any ordinary hunter.

But the men lacked the wits to effectively operate firearms,
and the weapon was quietly ushered into permanent storage.

Fist of Gratia: A chunk of iron fitted with finger holes.

The hulking hunter woman Simple Gratia, ever hopeless
when handling hunter firearms, preferred to knock the lights
out of the beasts with this hunk of iron, which incidentally
caused heavy stagger.

Gratia was a fearsome hunter, and to onlookers, her
unrelenting pummeling appeared oddly heroic. No wonder
the weapon later assumed her name.

Piercing Rifle: A rifle engineered by the Oto Workshop, the precursor to
the workshop of the heretical Powder Kegs.

Designed for hunting on narrow streets, this rifle has been
optimized to cause perforation wounds, but is unfit for
reliably countering attacks.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 45


Gatling Gun: This is a highly-customised, portable version of the
stationary gatling gun operated by the old hunter Djura in
Old Yharnam. It was the weapon of choice of the youngest
of Djura's three companions.

The Gatling Gun boasts exceptional rapid-firing
functionality, but is considered a cumbersome weapon, due
to its excessive weight and insatiable consumption of
Quicksilver Bullets.

Wooden Shield: A crude weapon shield used by the masses who have
arisen to join the hunt.

Hunters do not normally employ shields, ineffectual
against the strength of the beasts as they tend to be.

Shield are nice, but not if they engender passivity.

Hunter’s Torch: A torch formed by wrapping a pine resin-drenched cloth
around the end of a long stick. Once used in Old Yharnam.

Designed to incinerate beasts and victims touched by the
scourge.

Its fire damage is highly effective against beasts.

Torch: A common torch formed by wrapping a pine resin-drenched
cloth around the end of a long stick.

Hunters choose torches not only because the hunt leads
them to the darkest nooks, but also because certain creatures
they encounter are possessed of a deathly fear of flame.

Loch Shield: An artisanal shield crafted with blue glass.

Originally used to safeguard the leader presiding over a
sacred Healing Church ceremony, and later supplied to tomb
prospectors, in particular those exploring the labyrinth of
Isz.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 46


The blue is fashioned after a lake, and the shield greatly
reduces all forms of non-physical damage.


Upgrade Materials:
Blood Stone Shard: A solid shard that forms in coldblood.

After death, a substance in the blood hardens, and that
which does not crystallise is called a bloodstone.

At the workshop. these bloodstones are embedded in
weapons to fortify them.

Twin Blood Stone Shards: A solid shard that forms in coldblood.

After death, a substance in the blood hardens, and that
which does not crystallise is called a bloodstone.

At the workshop, these bloodstones are embedded in
weapons to fortify them.

Blood Stone Chunk: A solid chunk that forms in coldblood.

After death, a substance in the blood hardens, and that
which does not crystallise is called a blood stone.

A chunk will never appear in the blood of an ordinary
human. Seek deadlier foes if bloodstone chunks are needed.

Blood Rock: A large solid chunk that forms in coldblood.

After death, a substance in the blood hardens, and that
which does not crystallise is called a blood stone.

This is no mere chunk, it is nearly a boulder.

Few blood stones of such size have ever been discovered,
even considering the combined experience of all the hunters.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                               Script 47


Blood Gems:
Tempering Blood Gemstone: A blood gem that fortifies weapons and adds various
properties. Blood gems are especially rare blood stones that
grow on coldblood.

Blood gems are kneaded into weapons using workshop tools,
but only when of matching shape.

Most triangular blood gems have effects that provide attribute bonuses and extra effects.

Cursed Tempering Blood Gemstone: A blood gem that fortifies weapons and adds various
properties.

The sticky spots are indicative of a curse, but this gem's malicious effects are perfect for
bolstering certain types of weapons.

Most radial blood gems have effects that bear upon physical attacks.

Tempering Damp Blood Gem: A blood gem that fortifies weapons and adds various
properties. This particular specimen has a pronounced effect, due to its extended state of
dampness.

Most radial blood gems have effects that bear upon physical attacks.

Cursed Tempering Damp Blood Gem: A blood gem that forfortifies weapons and adds various
properties. The sticky spots are indicative of a curse, but this gem's malicious effect are perfect
for bolstering certain types of weapons

Droplet gems are special gems that adapt to various weapons and shapes, naturally making them
highly priced among hunters.

Adept Blood Gemstone: A blood gem that fortifies weapons and adds various
properties. Blood gems are especially rare blood stones that
grow on coldblood.

Blood gems are kneaded into weapons using workshop tools,
but only when of matching shape.

Most radial blood gems have effects that bear upon physical attacks.

        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                           Script 48


Cursed Heavy Abyssal Blood Gem: A blood gem that fortifies weapons and adds various
properties.

Abyssal blood gems are eldritch gems with a dim radiance that only grow deep inside the
labyrinth.

Most radial blood gems have effects that bear upon physical attacks, and if cursed, also exhibit
malicious effects.

Damp Blood Gem: A blood gem that fortifies weapons and adds various properties. This
particular specimen has a pronounced effect, due to its extended state of dampness.

Most waning blood gems provide rare special effects such as fire, bolt, or healing.

Gold Blood Gem: A blood gem that fortifies weapons and adds various properties.

Most radial blood gems have effects that bear upon physical attacks, and this golden radial blood
gem, kept for generations within the Church, strengthens attacks against those afflicted intensely
by beasthood.

When clerics began transforming into unspeakable beasts, the Church needed something to
retaliate with.

Tear Blood Gem: A blood gem that fortifies weapons and adds various properties.
Droplet blood gems are special gems that adapt to various weapons and shapes.

Created from a shining silver doll tear, this blood gem is a quiet but unfaltering friend that
continually restores HP, the life essence of a hunter. Perhaps the doll's creator had wished for
just such a friend, albeit in vain.

Red Blood Gem: A blood gem that fortifies weapons and adds various properties.

Droplet blood gems are special gems that adapt to various weapons and shapes.

Created from a bright-red brooch, this blood gem strengthens the effect of rallying. A
quintessential hunter skill, rallying symbolizes the battle-worn hunter who is often the only thing
standing after a bloodbath.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                         Script 49


Armor:
Ashen Hunter Set: Attire of the retired hunter Djura. Painted with ash in a ceremony to ward off
blood. Djura is known through his contact with the Powder Kegs, the heretics of the workshop.
He is said to have been both uncommonly kind and dreadfully foolish. Djura felt defeated by the
state of Old Yharnam, and renounced his hunter's vows.

Ashen Hunter Cap: Attire of the retired hunter Djura. This worn cap was the lone-wolf's
trademark. Djura is known through his contact with the Powder Kegs, the heretics of the
workshop. He is said to have been both uncommonly kind and dreadfully foolish. Djura felt
defeated by the state of Old Yharnam, and renounced his hunter's vows.

Black Church Hat: Attire of Healing Church hunters. Most Healing Church hunters are
elementary doctors who understand the importance of early prevention of
the scourge, achieved by disposing of victims, and even potential victims, before signs of
sickness manifest themselves. Their black attire is synonymous with fear, and that peculiar
Yharnam madness.

Black Church Garb: Attire of Healing Church hunters. The Holy Shawl, symbol of the Healing
Church, flutters proudly on their backs. Most Healing Church hunters are elementary doctors
who understand the importance of early prevention of the scourge, achieved by disposing of
victims, and even potential victims, before signs of sickness manifest themselves. Their black
attire is synonymous with fear, and that peculiar Yharnam madness.

Surgical Long Gloves: White surgical gloves. The intricate embroidery weaves a spell that
protects their wearer. The Church engages in the hunt in a medical capacity. When a cancer is
discovered, one must pinpoint its location, reach in, and wrench it from the host's bosom.

Black Church Trousers: Attire of Healing Church hunters. Most Healing Church hunters are
elementary doctors who understand the importance of early prevention of the scourge, achieved
by disposing of victims, and even potential victims, before signs of sickness manifest
themselves. Their black attire is synonymous with fear, and that peculiar Yharnam madness.

Bone Ash Mask: A mask made of bone ash, worn by the oldest keepers. The keepers, who mind
the slumbering great Ones, gained eternal life, preserved in ashen form in a ceremony of flame
that cremated body and soul. The long, pointed hat is a symbol of the old keepers
and is considered evidence of their companionship, forged in a certain sin.

Bone Ash Armor: Armor made of bone ash, worn by the oldest keepers. The keepers, who mind
the slumbering great Ones, gained eternal life, preserved in ashen form in a ceremony of flame

        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                            Script 50


that cremated body and soul. Now, their frail armor is white and sinewy, a window into an
arcane lost art.

Bone Ash Gauntlets: Gauntlets made of bone ash, worn by the oldest keepers. The keepers, who
mind the slumbering great Ones, gained eternal life, preserved in ashen form in a ceremony of
flame that cremated body and soul. Now, their frail armor is white and sinewy, a window into an
arcane lost art.

Bone Ash Leggings: Leggings made of bone ash, worn by the oldest keepers. The keepers, who
mind the slumbering Great Ones, gained eternal life, preserved in ashen form in a ceremony of
flame that cremated body and soul. Now, their frail armor is white and sinewy, a window into an
arcane lost art.

Cainhurst Helmet: Silver helmet worn by the royal guards who protect Annalise, Queen of the
Vilebloods at Cainhurst Castle. This paper-thin silver armor is said to deflect blood of ill-intent,
and is what allows the royal guards to capture prey for their beloved Queen, so that one day, she
may bear a Child of Blood.

Cainhurst Armor: Silver armor worn by the royal guards who protect Annalise, Queen of the
Vilebloods at Cainhurst Castle. This paper-thin silver armor is said to deflect blood of ill-intent,
and is what allows the royal guards to capture prey for their beloved Queen, so that one day, she
may bear a Child of Blood.

Cainhurst Gauntlets: Silver gauntlets worn by the royal guards who protect Annalise, Queen of
the Vilebloods at Cainhurst Castle. This paper-thin silver armor is said to deflect blood of ill-
intent, and is what allows the royal guards to capture prey for their beloved Queen, so that one
day, she may bear a Child of Blood.

Cainhurst Leggings: Silver leggings worn by the royal guards who protect Annalise, Queen of
the Vilebloods at Cainhurst Castle. This paper-thin silver armor is said to deflect blood of ill-
intent, and is what allows the royal guards to capture prey for their beloved Queen, so that one
day, she may bear a Child of Blood.

Rumpled Yharnam Hat: Common Yharnam cap. Well-worn and losing its shape.

Sweaty Clothes: Common Yharnam Clothing. Well-worn and damp with sweat.

Beak Mask: Wood-carved mask of Eileen the Crow, Hunter of Hunters. The beak contains
incense to mask scents of blood and beast. Hunters of Hunters dress as crows to suggest sky
burial. The first Hunter of Hunters came from a foreign land, and gave the dead a virtuous native


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                            Script 51


funeral ritual, rather than impose a blasphemous Yharnam burial service upon them, with the
hope that former compatriots might be returned to the skies, and find rest in a hunter's dream.

Crowfeather Garb: Attire worn by Eileen the Crow, Hunter of Hunters, known in particular for
her crowfeather cape. Hunters of Hunters dress as crows to suggest sky burial. The first Hunter
of Hunters came from a foreign land, and gave the dead a virtuous native funeral ritual, rather
than impose a blasphemous Yharnam burial service upon them, with the hope that former
compatriots might be returned to the skies, and find rest in a hunter's dream.

Crowfeather Manchettes: Attire worn by Eileen the Crow, Hunter of Hunters, known in
particular for her crowfeather cape. Hunters of Hunters dress as crows to suggest sky burial. The
first Hunter of Hunters came from a foreign land, and gave the dead a virtuous native funeral
ritual, rather than impose a blasphemous Yharnam burial service upon them, with the hope that
former compatriots might be returned to the skies, and find rest in a hunter's dream.

Crowfeather Trousers: Attire worn by Eileen the Crow, Hunter of Hunters, known in particular
for her crowfeather cape. Hunters of Hunters dress as crows to suggest sky burial. The first
Hunter of Hunters came from a foreign land, and gave the dead a virtuous native funeral ritual,
rather than impose a blasphemous Yharnam burial service upon them, with the hope that former
compatriots might be returned to the skies, and find rest in a hunter's dream.

Doll Hat: A discarded doll's hat, likely a spare for dress-up. A deep love for the doll can be
surmised by the fine craftsmanship of this article, and the care with which it was kept. It
borderlines on mania, and exudes a slight warmth.

Doll Clothes: Discarded doll clothing, likely a spare for dress-up. A deep love for the doll can be
surmised by the fine craftsmanship of this article, and the care with which it was kept. It
borderlines on mania, and exudes a slight warmth.

Doll Gloves: A discarded doll gloves, likely a spare for dress-up. A deep love for the doll can be
surmised by the fine craftsmanship of this article, and the care with which it was kept. It
borderlines on mania, and exudes a slight warmth.

Doll Skirt: Discarded doll skirt, likely a spare for dress-up. A deep love for the doll can be
surmised by the fine craftsmanship of this article, and the care with which it was kept. It
borderlines on mania, and exudes a slight warmth.

Gold Ardeo: The odd helmet worn by the band of Executioners commanded by the martyr
Logarius. The conical gold helmet, symbol of the executioners, represents luminosity, ambition,
and an unflagging resolve to face impurity, staring it down with stern, golden spirit. As the great


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                              Script 52


Logarius once said, "Acts of goodness are not always wise, and acts of evil are not always
foolish, but regardless, we shall always strive to be good."

Executioner Garb: Attire worn by the band of executioners commanded by the martyr
Logarius. Later became that basis for all Church attire, with its heavy draping of Holy Shawl. As
the great Logarius once said, "Acts of goodness are not always wise, and acts of evil are not
always foolish, but regardless, we shall always strive to be good."

Executioner Gloves: Gauntlets worn by the band of executioners commanded by the martyr
Logarius. The brass rivets are unique to the executioners, and reflect their adoration of hand-to-
hand combat. As the great Logarius once said, "Acts of goodness are not always wise, and acts
of evil are not always foolish, but regardless, we shall always strive to be good."

Executioner Trousers: Attire worn by the band of executioners commanded by the martyr
Logarius. Later became that basis for all Church attire. As the great Logarius once said, "Acts of
goodness are not always wise, and acts of evil are not always foolish, but regardless, we shall
always strive to be good."

Black Hood: Hood worn upon awakening to the nightmare of blood and beasts. Perhaps its
wearer had to stay out of sight, and travel by cover of darkness. Without memory, who will ever
know?

Foreign Garb: Clothing worn upon awakening to the nightmare of blood and beasts. Not typical
clothing of Yharnam, perhaps it is of foreign origin, It is said, after all, the traveler came to
Yharnam from afar. Without memory, who will ever know?

Sullied Bandage: Bandage worn upon awakening to the nightmare of blood and beasts. Terribly
worn and unsanitary. A faint memory recalls blood ministration, involving the transfusion of
unknown blood. Not long after, the nightmare began.

Foreign Trousers: Trousers worn upon awakening to the nightmare of blood and beasts. Not
typical clothing perhaps it is of foreign origin. It is said, after all, the traveler came to Yharnam
from afar. Without memory, who will ever know?

Gascoigne’s Set: Hunter attire worn by Father Gascoigne. Similar to the hunter garb created at
the workshop, only these are tainted by a pungent beastly stench that eats away at Gascoigne.
"Father" is a title used for clerics in a foreign land, and there is no such rank in the Healing
Church.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                           Script 53


Gascoigne’s Garb: Hunter attire worn by Father Gascoigne. The Dingy scarf is a Holy Shawl
and symbol of the Healing Church, from which Gascoigne would eventually part ways. "Father"
is a title used for clerics in a foreign land, and there is no such rank in the Healing Church.

Gehrman’s Set: Hunter attire of Gehrman, the first hunter. Created before the workshop existed
by making adjustments to everyday clothing, and later became the basis for all hunter's garb. The
hunter's emphasis on engaging beasts with speed, and therefore of selecting lightweight attire, no
doubt traces back to Gehrman's own combat style.

Graveguard Mask: Mask of Dores, graveguard of the Forbidden Woods. His pale countenance
mimics the labyrinth watchers. Willem kept two loyal servants back at Byrgenwerth. When they
were sent into the labyrinth, they encountered the eldritch Truth, and went mad. One became the
password gatekeeper, while Dores became a graveguard of the forest. Both remained loyal, even
in madness.

Graveguard Robe: Robe of Dores, graveguard of the Forbidden Woods. Countless bloodied
ritual tools hang from its back. Willem kept two loyal servants back at Byrgenwerth. When they
were sent into the labyrinth, they encountered the eldritch Truth, and went mad. One became the
password gatekeeper, while Dores became a graveguard of the forest. Both remained loyal, even
in madness.

Graveguard Manchettes: Manchettes of Dores, graveguard of the Forbidden Woods. Covered
in the blood of untidy rituals. Willem kept two loyal servants back at Byrgenwerth. When they
were sent into the labyrinth, they encountered the eldritch Truth, and went mad. One became the
password gatekeeper, while Dores became a graveguard of the forest. Both remained loyal, even
in madness.

Graveguard Kilt: Leggings of Dores, graveguard of the Forbidden Woods. Covered in the
blood of untidy rituals. Willem kept two loyal servants back at Byrgenwerth. When they were
sent into the labyrinth, they encountered the eldritch Truth, and went mad. One became the
password gatekeeper, while Dores became a graveguard of the forest. Both remained loyal, even
in madness.

Henryk’s Hunter Cap: Hunter's hat worn by Henryk, the old hunter. The taciturn old hunter
Henryk was once partners with Father Gascoigne, and though they were a fierce and gallant duo,
their partnership led to Henryk's tragically long life. Henryk's unique yellow garb is resistant to
bolt and will be of great help to any hunter who has inherited the onus of the hunt.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                           Script 54


Henryk’s Hunter Garb: Hunter's attire worn by Henryk, the old hunter. The taciturn old hunter
Henryk was once partners with Father Gascoigne, and though they were a fierce and gallant duo,
their partnership led to Henryk's tragically long life. Henryk's unique yellow garb is resistant to
bolt and will be of great help to any hunter who has inherited the onus of the hunt.

Henryk’s Hunter Gloves: Hunter's attire worn by Henryk, the old hunter. The taciturn old
hunter Henryk was once partners with Father Gascoigne, and though they were a fierce and
gallant duo, their partnership led to Henryk's tragically long life. Henryk's unique yellow garb is
resistant to bolt and will be of great help to any hunter who has inherited the onus of the hunt.

Henryk’s Hunter Trousers: Hunter's trousers worn by Henryk, the old hunter. The taciturn old
hunter Henryk was once partners with Father Gascoigne, and though they were a fierce and
gallant duo, their partnership led to Henryk's tragically long life. Henryk's unique yellow garb is
resistant to bolt and will be of great help to any hunter who has inherited the onus of the hunt.

Cape Hunter Set: One of the standard articles of hunter attire fashioned at the workshop. A fine
piece of hunter attire that provides stable defence to anyone facing Yharnam's beastly threat.
Allows one to stalk beats unannounced, by cover of night.

Charred Hunter Garb: One of the staple articles of hunter attire, fashioned at the workshop. A
product of the scourge of the beast that once plagued Old Yharnam and culminated in the town's
fiery cleansing. The cape's dampness makes it highly resistant to fire. Wearers of this attire
hunted down victims of the scourge who survived the raging flames and stench of singed blood.

Charred Hunter Set: One of the staple articles of hunter attire, fashioned at the workshop. A
product of the scourge of the beast that once plagued Old Yharnam and culminated in the town's
fiery cleansing. Designed to be highly resistant to fire. Wearers of this attire hunted down
victims of the scourge who survived the raging flames and stench of singed blood.

Blindfold Cap: Attire of the Choir, high-ranking members of the Healing Church. Members of
the Choir are both the highest-ranking clerics of the Healing Church, and scholars who continue
the work that began at Byrgenwerth. The eye covering indicates their debt to the teachings of
Master Willem, even though their paths diverged.

Choir Set: Attire of the Choir, high-ranking members of the Healing Church. Members of the
Choir are both the highest-ranking clerics of the Healing Church, and scholars who continue the
work that began at Byrgenwerth. Together with the left behind Great One, they look to the skies,
in search of astral signs, that may lead them to the rediscovery of true greatness.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                           Script 55


Knight’s Wig: Adornment prized by the knights of Cainhurst. Resembles a ponytail of silver
hair. The Cainhurst way is a mix of nostalgia and bombast. They take great pride even in the
blood-stained corpses of beasts that they leave behind, confident that they will stand as example
of decadent art.

Knight’s Garb: Attire of the knights of Cainhurst. A regal piece graced by intricate goldwork.
The Cainhurst way is a mix of nostalgia and bombast. They take great pride even in the blood-
stained corpses of beasts that they leave behind, confident that they will stand as examples of
decadent art.

Knight’s Gloves: Gloves of the knights of Cainhurst. A regal piece graced with goldwork on red
fabric. The Cainhurst way is a mix of nostalgia and bombast. They take great pride even in the
blood-stained corpses of beasts that they leave behind, confident that they will stand as examples
of decadent art.

Knight’s Trousers: Attire of the knights of Cainhurst. A regal piece made with the finest
leather. The Cainhurst way is a mix of nostalgia and bombast. They take great pride even in the
blood-stained corpses of beasts that they leave behind, confident that they will stand as examples
of decadent art.

Madman Hood: Most tomb prospectors, members of the Healing Church chose to explore the
old labyrinth, are unable to withstand the weight of the old knowledge, and go mad. This attire is
worn by those lost souls. Truth often resembles madness, inaccessible to the dull of mind. Those
who go mad are merely thoughtful souls who failed to reach any conclusions.

Madman Garb: Most tomb prospectors, members of the Healing Church chose to explore the
old labyrinth, are unable to withstand the weight of the old knowledge, and go mad. This attire is
worn by those lost souls. The appendages draped across them are said to be a kind of protective
charm, or at least, that is what these lost souls believe with all their hearts.

Madman Manchettes: Most tomb prospectors, members of the Healing Church chose to
explore the old labyrinth, are unable to withstand the weight of the old knowledge, and go mad.
This attire is worn by those lost souls. Truth often resembles madness, inaccessible to the dull of
mind. Those who go mad are merely thoughtful souls who failed to reach any conclusions.

Madman Leggings: Most tomb prospectors, members of the Healing Church chose to explore
the old labyrinth, are unable to withstand the weight of the old knowledge, and go mad. This
attire is worn by those lost souls. Truth often resembles madness, inaccessible to the dull of
mind. Those who go mad are merely thoughtful souls who failed to reach any conclusions.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                         Script 56


Cape Student Uniform: Uniform of the students of Byrgenwerth, a bygone institute of learning.
Features a thick cape. The Healing Church has its roots in Byrgenwerth, and naturally borrows
heavily from its uniform design. The focus not on knowledge, or thought, but on pure pretension
would surely bring Master Willem to despair, if only he knew.

Student Trousers: Uniform of the students of Byrgenwerth, a bygone institute of learning. The
Healing Church has its roots in Byrgenwerth, and naturally borrows heavily from its uniform
design. The focus not on knowledge, or thought, but on pure pretension would surely bring
Master Willem to despair, if only he knew.

Student Uniform: Uniform of the students of Byrgenwerth, a bygone institute learning. This
alternative lacks the thick cape. This Healing Church has its roots in Byrgenwerth, and naturally
borrows heavily from its uniform design. The focus not on knowledge, or thought, but on pure
pretension would surely bring Master Willem to despair, if only he knew.

Tomb Prospector Set: Attire of tomb prospectors who explore the old labyrinth on behalf of the
Healing Church. The Healing Church traces its roots to Byrgenwerth, and is therefore aware of
the ruins' true importance. They contain much more than mere hunter trinkets, indeed, they hide
the very secrets of the old Great Ones, sought after by those with the insight to imagine
greatness.

Top Hat: Hat worn by hunters who admire formality. Some hunters place an emphasis on form,
as seen by the use of the threaded cane. For them, formality, beauty, and justice are the very
essence of our humanity, and precisely what keeps hunters from becoming something else.

White Church Set: Attire of special Church doctors. These doctors are superiors to the black
preventative hunters, and specialists in experimentally-backed blood ministration and the
scourge of the beast. They believe that medicine is not a means of treatment but rather a method
for research, and that some knowledge can only be obtained by exposing oneself to sickness.

Black Hooded Iron Helm: Iron helmet worn by hunters of the Unseen Village. The hunters of
Yahar'gul answer to the village's founders, the School of Mensis. Hunters in name only, these
kidnappers wear their black hoods low to shadow their eyes. This helm is made of metal, a rarity
for hunter garb, and has high defence, but only against physical attacks.

Iron Yahar’gul Helm: Iron helmet worn by hunters of the Unseen Village. Removing the hood
reveals something reminiscent of a warrior of a previous age. This headwear is made of metal, a
rarity for hunter garb, and has high defense, but only against physical attacks.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                            Script 57


Yahar’gul Black Garb: Thick black pullover worn by hunters of the Unseen Village. The
hunters of Yahar'gul answer to the village's founders, the School of Mensis. Hunters in name
only, these kidnappers blend into the night wearing this attire. Designed primarily to defend from
physical attacks, the binding of thick rope serves both to protect its wearer, and restrain his foes.

Yahar’gul Black Gloves: Thick black gloves worn by hunters of the Unseen Village. The
hunters of Yahar'gul answer to the village's founders, the School of Mensis. Hunters in name
only, these kidnappers blend into the night wearing this attire. Designed primarily to defend from
physical attacks.

Yahar’gul Black Trousers: Thick black trousers worn by hunters of the Unseen Village. The
hunters of Yahar'gul answer to the village's founders, the School of Mensis. Hunters in name
only, these kidnappers blend into the night wearing this attire. Designed primarily to defend from
physical attacks.

Yharnam Hunter Set: Ludwig, the first hunter of the Healing Church, once recruited
Yharnamites to serve as hunters. This hunter's attire was made for new recruits, and has excellent
straightforward defense. But not nearly enough to allow an ordinary man to stand any real
chance against the beasts.

Brador’s Testimony: The scalp of a horrid cleric beast, indicating that hunter Brador, a Healing
Church assassin, had killed a compatriot. Afterward, he wore his ally's own scalp, and hid
himself away, deep below in a cell. The Church provided him with a single, soundless bell of
death, to ensure their secrets would be kept.

Beast Hide Garb: The bloodied hide of a horrible cleric beast, pulled over the back. Without the
attacked beast hide this foreigner garb wouldn't raise anyone's eyebrows. Brador donned a
compatriot's beastly scalp and hide while still moist with blood. Most of the blood stains on this
hide were from that day.

Bloodied Arm Bands: Bloodied arm bands. Brador donned a compatriot's beastly scalp and hide
while still moist with blood. Most of the blood stains on this hide were from that day.

Bloodied Trousers: Bloodied foreign trousers. Brador donned a compatriot's beastly scalp and
hid while still moist with blood. Most of the blood stains on this hide were from that day.

Butcher Mask: Mask of the Madaras twins, denizens of the Forbidden Woods, likely belonging
to the older of the two. The twins grew up in silent kinship with a poisonous snake. Eventually
they learned human ways, and became hunters. When they discovered vermin even in their
beloved snake, the younger brother is said to have murdered the older.


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                           Script 58


Butcher Garb: Garb of the Madaras twins, denizens of the Forbidden Woods, likely belonging
to the older of the two. Both the twins became hunters, and brought back and dissected their
beast prey, in order to support the villagers in their forbidden research.

Butcher Gloves: Gloves of the Madaras twins, denizens of the Forbidden Woods, likely
belonging to the older of the two. Both the twins became hunters, and brought back and dissected
their beast prey, in order to support the villagers in their forbidden research.

Butcher Trousers: Trousers of the Madaras twins, denizens of the Forbidden Woods, likely
belonging to the older of the two. Both the twins became hunters, and brought back and dissected
their beast prey, in order to support the villagers in their forbidden research.

One-eyed Iron Helm: An iron helm resembling an upside-down bucket. A single hole allows
one to peek out with a single eye, which is probably all that its original owner had.

Master’s Iron Helm: An iron helm resembling an upside-down bucket. A single hole allows
one to peek out with a single eye, which is probably all that its original owner had. The iron helm
is passed down among masters of the League. Valtr had in fact lost the ability to see vermin long
ago.

Constable Set: Once upon a time, a troupe of foreign constables chased a beast all the way to
Yharnam, and this is what they wore. The constables became victims of the beast, except for one
survivor, who in turn devoured the creature whole, all by himself. The fable is a favorite among
Yharnamites, who are partial to any stories of pompous, intolerant foreigners who suffer for their
ignorance. It makes the blood taste that much sweeter.

Decorative Old Hunter Set: Old hunter garb decorated with brass trinkets. At the time, some
hunters believed that certain metals would ward off beast blood. On a night of the hunt, it is no
wonder that people would resort to superstition.

Old Hunter Cap: Old Hunter Cap with a wide brim that hides their sharp gaze. In the old days,
when hunters were ten a penny, this was part of their standard garb.

Old Hunter Top Hat: Old hunter top hat, warped by blood stains. In the old days, when hunters
were ten a penny, this was part of their standard garb.

Old Hunter Garb: Old hunter garb. One day, the hunters disappeared, and Yharnamites began
to whisper of the hunters' sin. Drunk with blood, chasing after beasts, they would pass on to the
Nightmare, every last one of them.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                            Script 59


Old Hunter Gloves: Old hunter gauntlets made of brass to protect their weapon-bearing hands.
At the time, some hunters believed that certain metals would ward off beast blood. On a night of
the hunt, it is no wonder that people would resort to superstition.

Old Hunter Trousers: Old hunter trousers that protected countless hunters from the beasts in an
older age. A widespread belief of the period was that "beast blood crept up the right leg," and
this led to the double-wrapped belt.

Harrowed Set: Certain Church hunters obfuscate their identities and slip into the nooks and
crannies of the city. This is the garb that allows these harrowed individuals to go unnoticed.
These hunters are keen to early signs of the scourge, serving as a first line of defense against its
outbreak. Or perhaps, when the time is ripe, they find signs of the scourge where there are none.
It just goes to show, the corner beggar is not always who he seems.

Lady Maria’s Set: Among the first hunters, all students of Gehrman, was the lady hunter Maria.
This was her hunter's cap, crafted in Cainhurst. Maria is distantly related to the undead queen,
but had great admiration for Gehrman, unaware of his curious mania.

Yamamura Hunter Hat: A standard hunter's hat, worn by Yamamura the Wanderer. This hat
and staff were given to him when he became a hunter and confederate of the League.

Khaki Haori: Garb of a distant Eastern land, worn by Yamamura the Wanderer. This Eastern
warrior pursued a beast for honourable revenge, then became a hunter of the League. But when
he stared straight into impurity, it drove him mad.

Old Hunter Arm Bands: Old Hunter arm bands wound tightly to prevent infection with the
scourge. Of course, the idea that the scourge was infectious was pure hearsay.

Wine Hakama: Garb of a distant Eastern land, worn by Yamamura the Wanderer. This Eastern
warrior pursued a beast for honourable revenge, then became a hunter of the League. But when
he stared straight into impurity, it drove him mad.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 60


Key Items:
Cainhurst Badge: Badge of the royal guards of Cainhurst, loyal guardians of
the Vileblood Queen Annalise.

The Vilebloods are hunters of blood, and hunt prey as they
search for blood dregs. The hunter who joins them is faced
with a decision: to merely borrow their strength, or to
become one of them, heart and soul.

Cosmic Eye Watcher Badge: Badge of a member of the Choir, elites of the
Healing Church.

The eye signifies the very cosmos.

The Choir stumbled upon an epiphany, very suddenly and
quite by accident. Here we stand, feet planted in the earth,
but might the cosmos be very near us, only just above our
heads?

Crow Hunter Badge: Badge of a hunter of hunters, who hunts those who
have become intoxicated by their bloodlust.

The badge of the hunter of hunters is quitly
passed down from generation to generation,
usually to an outsider from the hinterlands.

To be entrusted with this cursed badge, one must
be strong, resilient to the seduction of blood,
and gracious when taking a comrade's life.

Old Hunter Badge: This hunter's badge, crafted in Gehrman's time, has no
practical purpose, except perhaps to assist in romanticising
about the past.

The badge was a special privilege for the hunters of the past,
and should not be dishonoured.

It should be left in peace, unless one is truly prepared to
assume the will of those gone before.

        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                    Script 61


Powder Keg Hunter Badge: Badge crafted by the Powder Kegs, the heretics of the
Workshop.

The Powder Kegs aboration of complex design and big
booms culminated in weapon designs that contrast with
those traditionally of the Workshop.

The late Powder Kegs, bless their souls, had a motto:
"If a weapon ain't got kick, it just ain't worth it."

Radiant Sword Hunter Badge: One of the badges crafted by the Healing Church.

The radiant sword indicates the heirs to the will of Ludwig.

These hunters, also known as Holy Blades, are what remains
of an ancient line of heroes that date back to a very early
age of honour and chivalry.

Saw Hunter Badge: Badge crafted long ago at the Workshop. Attests to one's
prowess as a hunter of beasts.

The Workshop is gone, and no group recognises this
meaningless badge, except the messengers in the bath, who
understand its profundity.

Certain things can only be entrusted with a hunter in
possession of this badge, or so they believe.

Spark Hunter Badge: Badge crafted in secret by Archibald, the infamous eccentric
of the Healing Church, for his friends.

Archibald was fascinated by the blue sparks that emanate
from the hides of the darkbeasts, and dedicated his life to its
artificial reproduction, in a style of inquiry that, incidentally,
closely followed the methodology of Byrgenwerth.

Sword Hunter Badge: One of the badges crafted by the Healing Church.
The silver sword is a symbol of a Church hunter.

Ludwig was the first of many Healing Church hunters to


         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 62


come, many of whom were clerics. As it was, clerics
transformed into the most hideous beasts.

Wheel Hunter Badge: Martyr Logarius led a band of Executioners, and this badge
was crafted at their dedicated workshop. The wheel
symbolizes righteous destiny.

Their workshop was a secretive enclave of mystical beliefs
and heady fanaticism which served as the backbone of the
Executioners' unique brand of justice.

Firing Hammer Badge: Badge crafted by the Oto Workshop, precursor to the
workshop of the heretical Powder Kegs.

The Powder Kegs were driven by singular ideas, and crafted
strange weapons of great intricacy.
It is clear that the philosophy of the Powder Kegs was
already established at this time.

Cainhurst Summons: An old blood-stained summons, inviting an honored guest
to the forsaken Castle Cainhurst.

Rather bafflingly, it is addressed to you.

Do not hesitate; the stagecoach leaves from Hemwick crossing.

Hunter Chief Emblem: A cloth emblem that belonged to the captain of the Church
hunters long ago. Opens the main gate that leads to the
round plaza of the Great Cathedral.

The main gate is shut tight on nights of the hunt, and could
only be opened from the other side with this emblem. In
other words, the captain's return, and this
emblem, determined the end of the hunt.

Iron Door Key: Of the three great bridges that link the two cathedral
cradles, this key opens the iron door that leads to the
midlevel bridge.

There are no thieves in the nightmare. Then, why lock a


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                    Script 63


door? Be warned, there must be a very, very good reason.

Lecture Theatre Key: Key to the Lecture Theatre in the Lecture Building.

Today, the two-story Lecture Building is adrift in the
nightmare, but once it was a place of reflection, where
scholars learned of history and archaeology.

Perhaps it still is, as the students in the lecture theatre
appear to await the return of their professor.

Lunarium Key: Key to the lunarium facing the lake on the second floor of
Byrgenwerth College.

In his final years, Master Willem was fond of the lookout,
and the rocking chair that he kept there for meditation.
In the end, it is said, he left his secret with the lake.

Oedon Tomb Key: Key to the gate that blocks the Tomb of Oedon.

Beyond the tomb, Oedon Chapel can be found in the center
of the Cathedral Ward.

Only today the church is abandoned, and some say that the
residents of Oedon have all gone mad.

Old Hunter Bell: One of the resonating bells that cross the gaps of worlds.
This bell is cracked and stained with the blood of beasts.

A human must expend Insight to ring this uncanny bell.

The old hunters, who have long passed from the dream but
cannot forget the feeling of the hunt, rely upon messengers
to relay their thoughts.
Ring the bell at their side, and they are certain to give a listen.
For the night of the hunt is long, and unchanging.




         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                           Script 64


Orphanage Key: Key to the Orphanage, birthplace of the Choir.

The Orphanage, shadowed by the Grand Cathedral, was a
place of scholarship and experimentation, where young
orphans became potent unseen thinkers for the Healing
Church.

The Choir, that would later split from the Healing Church,
was a creation of the Orphanage.

Queenly Flesh: What remains of Annalise, blood queen of Cainhurst.

This pinkish lump of flesh remains warm, as if cursed.
All hail the undying queen of blood!

Ring of Betrothal: The inhuman beings known as the Great Ones imbued this
ring of betrothal with some special meaning.

In the age of the Great Ones, wedlock was a blood contract,
only permitted to those slated to bear a special child.

Short Ritual Root Chalice: One of the root chalices that breaks various seals in the Old
Labyrinth.

The glass chalice, when full, is used in a short ritual to
quickly create and join a Chalice Dungeon (not for use in a
ritual using standard materials).

Short rituals are conducted at the makeshift altar.

Small Hair Ornament: A small, very ordinary hair ornament.

Although it has been lost for quite some time, one can still
see signs of the care with which this tasteful ornament was
once kept.

Its colour would stand out most brilliantly against a head of
greyish hair.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                    Script 65


Tonsil Stone: A latticed, deformed rock, or perhaps a meteorite.

Appears useless, but possesses some old gravitational force
that prevents its riddance. A dubious soul once said:

"Step lightly round to the right of the great cathedral, and
seek an ancient, shrouded church... The gift of the godhead
will grant you strength..."

Unopened Summons: An old, sealed summons.

Like the first of its kind, it is an invitation to Cainhurst, but
for whom is not known, as it lacks addressee.

Upper Cathedral Key: The key to the Upper Cathedral Ward seal.

The upper echelons of the Healing Church are formed by the
School of Mensis, based in the Unseen Village, and the Choir
occupying the Upper Cathedral Ward.

This key brings one a step closer to the Choir.

Yharnam Stone: A sacred heirloom left by Yharnam, Pthumerian Queen.

The Queen lies dead, but her horrific consciousness
is only asleep, and stirs in unsettling motions.

Astral Clocktower Key: Key to the Astral Clocktower at the top of the Grand
Cathedral.

The caretaker of the tower's numerous patients, known to
them only as Lady Maria, made her home behind the giant
star-interpreting clock.

Balcony Key: Key to the balcony on the first floor of the Research Hall.

Lady Maria of the Astral Clocktower gave this to the patient,
Adeline.

Maria had hoped Adeline would find comfort in the faint


         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                    Script 66


breeze that carried the scent of flowers from the outside, but
Adeline couldn't fathom her intentions.

First Brain Fluid: Greyish amoeba-shaped brain fluid. Wobbles and bounces.

Extracted from a patient whose head expanded until that
was all that they were.

In the early days of the Healing Church, the Great Ones were
linked to the ocean, and so the cerebral patients would imbibe
water, and listen for the howl of the sea. Brain fluid writhed
inside the head, the initial makings of internal eyes.

Second Brain Fluid: Greyish amoeba-shaped brain fluid. Wobbles and bounces.

Extracted from a patient whose head expanded until that
was all that they were.

Once, a young girl had an older brother who was determined to
become a doctor, and so she wilfully became his patient. In the
end, this led to their encounter with the Eldritch Truth,
for which they considered themselves blessed.

Adeline’s Brain Fluid: Greyish amoeba-shaped brain fluid. Wobbles and bounces.

Extracted from a patient whose head expanded until that
was all that they were.

We fail to realize our own latent potential, until the
moment it is lost, and we sense its absence. Ironically,
this is the very nature of insight, like the moment one
licks one's own blood, only to be startled by its sweetness.

Celestial Dial: A celestial dial that functions with the giant Astral Clock in
the Grand Cathedral.

When the dial is held up towards the Astral Clock, the clock
will come to life, and reveal a secret to its curious interloper.




         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                      Script 67


Eye of a blood-drunk Hunter: The eye of a blood-drunk hunter. Its pupil is collapsed and
turned to mush, indicating the onset of the scourge of beasts.

A hunter who goes drunk with blood is said to be taken by
the Nightmare, destined to wander forever, engaged in an
endless hunt. It is a fate that no hunter can escape.

Eye Pendant: An eye pendant which unlocks the surgery altar.

There are two cathedrals in the Hunter's Dream. One lies
past the River of Blood, and another contains the private
research hall of the Healing Church.

Only chosen members of the Healing Church, or their
lamentable patients, can enter the research hall, using this
eye.

Grant eyes to the surgery altar skull.

Laurence’s Skull: Skull of Laurence, first vicar of the Healing Church.
In reality he became the first cleric beast, and his human
skull only exists within the Nightmare.

The skull is a symbol of Laurence's past, and what he failed
to protect. He is destined to seek his skull, but even if he
found it, it could never restore his memories.

Underground Cell Inner Chamber Key: Key to the inner chamber of the cell below the Grand
Cathedral.

The innermost chamber of the underground cell holds a lone
madman. He wears a beast hide, and rings a bell that emits
no sound.

Unending death awaits those who can hear the soundless
bell.

Underground Cell Key: Key to the cell below the Grand Cathedral.

Hunters are held within the underground cell, so that things


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 68


better left unseen, and knowledge better left unknown, will
decay quietly in the fallow darkness.

Blood Gem Workshop Tool: A misplaced workshop tool from the Hunter's Dream.

The hunter who retrieves this can fortify weapons by
kneading blood gems into them.

Blood gems add properties to weapons when used to
fortify them, as blood defines an organism.

Rune Workshop Tool: Runesmith Caryll, student of Byrgenwerth, transcribed the
inhuman utterings of the Great Ones into what are now
called Caryll Runes.

The hunter who retrieves this workshop tool can etch Caryll
Runes into the mind to attain their wondrous strength.

Provost Willem would have been proud of Caryll's runes, as
they do not rely upon blood in any measure.

Workshop Haze Extractor: A misplace workshop tool from the Hunter's Dream.

The hunter who retrieves this can extract Arcane Haze
from ritual materials.

But alas, spent materials are lost.

Black Messenger Hat: Hat that messengers are oddly fond of.
Symbol of the preventative hunters of
the Healing Church.

The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an
interest in adornment. Why not let them be happy,
and revel as babes?

Blood Messenger Head Bandage: Accessory adored by naive messengers imitating
the bandages of scourge victims, unaware of their meaning.
The spatters of blood give it a particularly
nice touch.


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 69


The inhabitants of the stomp appear to have an
interest in adornment. Why not let them be happy,
and revel as babes?

Messenger Head Bandage: Accessory adored by naїve messengers imitating the
bandages of scourge victims, unaware of their meaning.

The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in
adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?

Messenger Top Hat: Hat that messengers are oddly fond of.

A nice top hat rounds out any Yharnam gentleman.

The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in
adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?

Messenger Urn Festival: Accessory adored by naїve messengers.

The messengers wear the urns, filled with incense that wards
off beasts, on their heads upside-down, suggesting a
predilection to the dark.

The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in
adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?

Red Messenger Ribbon: Red ribbon that messengers are oddly fond of.

The thick, pungent red was drawn from the organs
of some unfortunate victim.

A strange choice indeed, but perhaps for the messengers
wearing this accessory constitutes a form of mourning.

White Messenger Ribbon: White ribbon that messengers are oddly fond of.

A ribbon made of fine lace that shines remarkably,
more suited to pretty young girls than silly old
messengers.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                     Script 70


Worn Messenger Top Hat: A worn, rumpled top hat that messengers are oddly fond of.

The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest in
adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as babes?

Yharnam Messenger Hat: Hat that messengers are oddly fond of.

Commonly called a Yharnam hat.

The inhabitants of the stump appear to have an interest
in adornment. Why not let them be happy, and revel as
babes?


Consumables:
Antidote: Small medicinal tablets that counteract poison.

Used to treat ashen blood, the baffling sickness that ravaged
Old Yharnam long ago.

These tablets only provide short-term relief. The ashen blood
ailment eventually triggered the spread of the beastly
scourge.

Beast Blood Pellet: Large medicinal pellets, supposedly formed of coagulated
beast blood. Banned by the Healing Church due to
their unclear origin. Grants a spurt of beasthood.

Ripping apart the flesh of one's enemies and being
rained upon by their splattering blood invigorates
one's sense of beasthood, feeding strength and
euphoric feeling alike.

Blood of Adella: Blood taken from Adella, nun of the Healing Church.
Restores an amount of HP, then continues to gradually
restore HP for a short time.

The Healing Church nuns are chosen for their merit as
vessels for blood, and groomed as Blood Saints.


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 71


The mere chance of being treated with their blood lends
legitimacy to the Healing Church and communion.

Blood of Arianna: Blood taken from Arianna, Cathedral Ward woman of
pleasure. The sweet blood of Arianna restores HP, and
temporarily speeds stamina recovery.

A member of the old Healing Church would know that her
blood is similar to precisely what was once forbidden.

Blood Vial: Special blood used in ministration. Restores HP.

Once a patient has had their blood ministered, a unique but
common treatment in Yharnam, successive infusions recall
the first, and are all the more invigorating for it.

No surprise that most Yharnamites are heavy users of blood.

Great One’s Wisdom: Fragments of the lost wisdom of the Great Ones, beings that
might be described as gods.

Use to gain Insight.

At Byrgenwerth, Master Willem had an epiphany:
"We are thinking on the basest of planes. What we need, are
more eyes."

Iosefka’s Blood Vial: Blood vial acquired from Iosefka's clinic.

This refined blood, highly invigorating,
restores a larger amount of HP.

The product of a slow and careful refinement process,
this rare blood vial appears to be a clinic original.

Madman’s Knowledge: Skull of a madman touched by the wisdom of
the Great Ones.

Use to gain Insight.
Making contact with eldritch wisdom is a blessing,


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                         Script 72


for even if it drives one mad,
it allows one to serve a grander purpose, for posterity.

Sedatives: Liquid medicine concocted at Byrgenwerth.
Calms the nerves.

Those who delve into the arcane fall all-too-easily
to madness, and thick human blood serves to calm
the frayed nerves of these inquisitive minds. Naturally,
this often leads to a reliance on blood ministration.

Workshop Third Umbilical Cord: A great relic, also known as the Cord of the Eye. Every
infant Great One has this precursor to the umbilical cord.

Every Great One loses its child, and then yearns for a surrogate. The Third Umbilical Cord
precipitated the encounter with the pale moon, which beckoned the hunters and conceived the
hunter's dream.

Use to gain Insight and, so they say, eyes on the inside, although no one remembers what that
truly entails.

Arianna’s Third Umbilical Cord: A great relic, also known as the Cord of the Eye. Every
infant Great One has this precursor to the umbilical cord.

Every Great One loses its child, and then yearns for a surrogate, and Oedon, the formless Great
One, is no different. To think, it was corrupted blood that began this eldritch liaison.

Use to gain Insight and, so they say, eyes on the inside, although no one remembers what that
truly entails.

“Iosefka’s” Third Umbilical Cord: A great relic, also known as the Cord of the Eye. Every
infant Great One has this precursor to the umbilical cord.

Provost Willem sought the Cord in order to elevate his being and thoughts to those of a Great
One, by lining his brain with eyes. The only choice, he knew, if man were to ever match Their
greatness.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                        Script 73


Mergo’s Third Umbilical Cord: A great relic, also known as the Cord of the Eye. Every infant
Great One has this precursor to the umbilical cord.

Every Great One loses its child, and then yearns for a surrogate. This Cord granted Mensis
audience with Mergo, but resulted in the stillbirth of their brains.

Use to gain Insight and, so they say, eyes on the inside, although no one remembers what that
truly entails.

Blood of Adeline: Blood taken from Adeline, patient of the research hall.
Restores HP, and continues to rejuvenate HP for some time.

Adeline was originally one of the Blood Saints who received
treatment by the Church to cultivate worthy blood. Adeline's
was one of the few cases that turned out favorably.

Lead Elixir: A heavy, syrupy liquid medicine.
Temporarily shifts weight to make deflection of attacks
easier, but must be used with care, as it also slows
movement with no change to defense.

Its recipe for this mysterious concoction is unknown, but
some postulate that it materializes only within the most
desperate nightmares.

Blue Elixir: Dubious liquid medicine used in strange experiments
conducted by high ministers of the Healing Church.

A type of anesthetic that numbs the brain.

Hunters, able to retain consciousness by force of will, make
use of a secondary effect of the medicine, which dilutes their
presence while standing still.

Bold Hunter’s Mark: Dubious liquid medicine used in strange experiments
conducted by high ministers of the Healing Church.

A type of anesthetic that numbs the brain.

Hunters, able to retain consciousness by force of will, make


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                       Script 74


use of a secondary effect of the medicine, which dilutes their
presence while standing still.

Hunter’s Mark: Dangling, upside-down rune etched in one's mind.
Symbol of a hunter.

By focusing one's thoughts on this rune, a hunter
loses all Blood Echoes, but awakens afresh,
as if it were all just a bad dream.


Weapon Buffs:
Bolt Paper: Coarse paper that applies bolt to weapons when rubbed.

Invented by Archibald, the infamous eccentric of the Healing
Church workshop. Artificially recreates the blue sparks that
are said to surround darkbeasts.

Unlike the other strange weapons created by Archibald, this
one was favored by many hunters, in particular those who
had even once laid eyes on a darkbeast.

Bone Marrow Ash: Additional medium that strengthens Quicksilver Bullets.

According to the workshop, this is a special bone marrow
ash collected from Hemwick Charnel Lane.

Invaluable to hunters with weak bloodtinge who require the use of stronger firearms.

Fire Paper: Coarse paper that applies fire to weapons when rubbed.

A hunter tool found in the Healing Church workshop.

Since the tragedy that struck Old Yharnam, fire has become
a staple in beast hunts, and is thought to cleanse impurity.

Certain types of beasts have an abnormal fear of flame.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                    Script 75


Throwable Items:
Molotov Cocktail: Explodes in raging flames when thrown against an object.
One of the oldest hunter tools available in the workshop.

Since the tragedy that struck Old Yharnam, fire has become
a staple in beast hunts, and is thought to cleanse impurity.

Certain types of beasts have an abnormal fear of flame.

Oil Urn: When this urn hits its mark, the target is drenched in oil, and
made extremely flammable.

Fire is commonplace on the hunt, and oil urns accentuate its
effect. Sometimes, when hunters burn beasts, they appear
intoxicated by the euphoria of purification.

Pebbles: Small Pebbles found throughout Yharnam.

Can be thrown at foes.

Quite thrilling.

Poison Knife: A knife slathered in poison.

This curved knife is as thin and sharp as a surgeon's blade.
Often used for self-defence by special doctors in the Healing
Church.

They say that hunters traditionally avoid the use of poison,
likely because the poison is too slow to act in the heat of the hunt.

Quicksilver Bullets: Special bullets used with hunter firearms.

Ordinary bullets have no effect on beasts,
and so Quicksilver Bullets, fused with the wielder's
own blood, must be employed.

The strength of Quicksilver Bullets depends greatly
upon wielder's bloodtinge.

         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 76


Rope Molotov Cocktail: Exploding molotov cocktail that is thrown behind.

Allows for more maneuvering compared to an ordinary
Molotov cocktail, and can catch foes off guard.

Since the tragedy that struck Old Yharnam, fire has become
a staple in beast hunts, and is thought to cleanse impurity.

Certain types of beasts have an abnormal fear of flame.

Shaman Bone Blade: A blade of bone coated with gruesome spinal fluid.
Used by old labyrinth watchers, in particular, those presiding
over rituals.

When victim is cut by this blade, the green spinal fluid
temporarily numbs the senses, disturbing the target's gross
motor skills. The blade, never intended for battle, must cut
deep to be effective, and breaks.

Throwing Knife: Throwing knife with a finely serrated blade.

One of the old hunter Henryk's favorite weapons.

Does not cause a great deal of damage to beasts, but with
deft use, can distract attackers and keep them at bay.

Delayed Molotov: A special hunter tool crafted by the old Oto Workshop.
These molotovs wedge into the ground when thrown, and
explode on a timed delay.

A shame that such a complex gadget must be sacrificed with
each use of this inefficient hunter tool. Nevertheless, delayed
molotovs are cherished by the minority of hunters who
prefer the tricksier kill. This creation is one of the earliest-
known roots of the Powder Kegs.

Delayed Rope Molotov: A special hunter tool crafted by the old Oto Workshop.
These molotovs wedge into the ground when thrown behind
one's back, and explode on a timed delay.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 77


A shame that such a complex gadget must be sacrificed with
each use of this inefficient hunter tool. Nevertheless, delayed
molotovs are cherished by the minority of hunters who
prefer the tricksier kill. This creation is one of the earliest-
known roots of the Powder Kegs.

Pungent Blood Cocktail: Mature blood cocktail that releases a pungent odor when
thrown that attracts blood-thirsty beasts.

A precious tool in sadly short supply.

In Yharnam, they produce more blood than alcohol, as the
former is the more intoxicating.

Numbing Mist: Throw to create a mist cloud that numbs a hunter's life
essence and prevents restoration of HP.

Said to be used by the blood hunters of Cainhurst, its recipe
is a secret closely guarded by the line of nobles inhabiting
the castle.


Misc:
Blood Dreg: The Vilebloods of Cainhurst, blood-lusting hunters,
see these frightful things in coldblood.

They often appear in the blood of echo fiends, that is to say,
the blood of hunters. Queen Annalise partakes in these blood
dregs offerings, so that she may one day bear the Child of
Blood, the next Vileblood heir.

Gold Pendant: Pendant of Vicar Amelia. Use to change into a Blood Gem,
which fortifies weapons.

This pendant, passed down among the vicars who head the Healing Church,
is a reminder of the cautionary adage. To reveal the adage,
touch the altar skull.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                        Script 78


Hand Lantern: Small portable lantern.

This hunting accessory provides light while leaving
both hands free to hold weapons. The torch, however, provides a stronger source of light.

Monocular: Monocular used to View things up close.

Not a hunter's tool, but a simple antique, to be used as one sees fit.

Red Jeweled Brooch: A woman's bright-red brooch, engraved with the name Viola.

Perhaps the jewel is a gift from a hunter. Use to change into
a droplet blood gem that fortifies any weapon.

With the proper workshop tool, various weapons can be
fortified.

Shining Coins: Various coins that are particularly luminous.

There are very few uses for spare change during the hunt,
but these will serve as guides through the darkness.

Or, one could save them until morning, if it ever comes.

Tear Stone: Silver-shining tear stone.

Use to change into a droplet blood gem that fortifies any
weapon.

A doll sheds neither blood nor tears, and thus its nature
remains unknown.

Tiny Music Box: A small music box received from a young Yharnam girl.
Plays a song shared by her mother and father.

Inside the lid is a small scrap of paper, perhaps an old
message. Two names can be made out, however faintly.

Viola and Gascoigne.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 79


Vermin: A centipede-like creature discovered on successful hunts by
League hunters.

Vermin, found hidden within filth, are only seen by League
confederates, and are the root of man's impurity. The League
has assumed the task of finding and crushing all vermin.

Perhaps there is some mercy in the madness. Those who
wish to see vermin can, and those who choose to are
provided with boundless purpose.


Coldblood:
Coldblood Dew: Droplet of coldblood containing Blood Echoes.

Use to gain Blood Echoes.

Hunters sustained by the dream gain strength from Blood
Echoes. They imbibe the blood with thoughts of reverence,
indeed gratitude, for their victims.

Thick Coldblood: A thick droplet of coldblood containing Blood Echoes.

Use to gain a larger amount of Blood Echoes.

A strong will produces thick blood. Doubtless, the product of
obsession, a potent source of human strength.

Frenzied Coldblood: A rich droplet of coldblood containing Blood Echoes.

Use to gain frenzied Blood Echoes.

This manifestation of madness comes from a mind teetering
on the very brink, but has a sane mind ever produced
anything of true significance?

Kin Coldblood: Coldblood of inhuman kin of the cosmos, brethren of the
Great Ones.

Use to gain unspeakable Blood Echoes.

        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                      Script 80


Dare not to delve into the world beyond humanity, the
eldritch Truth touched upon long ago at Byrgenwerth.

Great One Coldblood: Relic containing the Blood Echoes of a Great One.

Use to gain cosmically nightmarish Blood Echoes.

Like a true revelation, this uncanny relic defies
understanding.

Old Great One Coldblood: Relic containing the Blood Echoes of an Old Great One.

Use to gain cosmically nightmarish Blood Echoes.

Like a true revelation, this uncanny relic defies
understanding.

Revered Great One Coldblood*: Relic containing the blood echoes of a revered Great One.

Use to gain cosmically nightmarish Blood Echoes.

Like a true revelation, this uncanny relic defies
understanding
*Has not been found through normal means



Arcane/Bloodtinge Tools:
A Call Beyond: One of the secrets of the Choir.

Long ago, the Healing Church used phantasms to reach a
lofty plane of darkness, but failed to make contact with the
outer reaches of the cosmos.

The rite failed to achieve its intended purpose, but instead
created a small exploding star, now a powerful part of the
Choir's arsenal.
At times, failure is the mother of invention.

Augur of Ebrietas: One of the secret rites of the Choir,
high-ranking members of the Healing Church.

           ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                    Script 81



Use spirits, the invertebrates known to be augurs of
the Great Ones, to partially summon abandoned Ebrietas.

One of the few rites that allow one to directly utilize
the power of the Great Ones, and evidence that
the Choir had approached the eldritch Truth.

Beast Roar: One of the forbidden hunter tools
made by Irreverent Izzy.

Borrow the strength of the terrible undead darkbeasts,
if only for a moment, to blast surrounding foes back with
the force of a roaring beast.

The indescribable sound is broadcast with the caster's
own vocal cords, which begs the question, what terrible
things lurk deep within the frames of men?

Empty Phantasm Shell: Empty invertebrate shell that is said to be a familiar of a
Great One. The Healing Church has discovered a great
variety of invertebrates, or phantasms, as they are called.

Shells with slime still harbour arcane power, and can be
rubbed on weapons to imbue them with their strength.

Executioner's Gloves: One of the secret treasures hidden in Cainhurst.
The gloves of an executioner from a faraway land.

Passed from executioner father to executioner son,
these gloves can be used to summon wrathful spirits
of the past by smearing them with blood.

It is said that the nobles found in immeasurable delight
in the dances of these vengeful specters.

Choir Bell: Special hunter tool of the Choir, high-ranking
member of the church. Fashioned after a bell that
projects an arcane sound across planes of existence.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 82


The sound of this smaller, silver version of the bell
does not cross planes, but grants vigor and healing
to all cooperators.

Messenger’s Gift: A strange gift from the messengers, inhabitants of
the dream who revere the brave hunters.

Use to envelop oneself in a black nightmarish mist,
then transform into a messenger. The illusion is a parlor
trick, and any large movement will break the spell.

To preserve the guise, proceed very slowly.

Old Hunter Bone:
The bone of an old hunter whose name is lost.

It is said that he was an apprentice to old Gehrman, and a
practitioner of the art of Quickening, a technique particular
to the first hunters.

It is most appropriate that hunters, carriers of the torch who
are sustained by the dream, would tease an old art from his
remains.

Tiny Tonitrus: Tonitrus is a unique weapon crafted by Archibald,
the infamous eccentric of the Healing Church workshop.

This is a similar morning star mace that utilizes
Quicksilver Bullets. When struck into the ground,
it recreates the blue sparks that are said to surround
the darkbeasts.

Like Archibald's masterpiece, this too
is a superb conductor of the powerful blue sparks.

Accursed Brew: Skull of a local from the violated fishing village. The inside
of the skull was forcibly searched for eyes, as evidenced by
innumerable scratches and indentations.

No wonder the skull became stewed in curses.


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 83



They who offer baneful chants.
Weep with them, as one in trance.

Blacksky Eye: Soft eye blessed by a phantasm. They were
discovered through Byrgenwerth's contact with the
arcane, but in the end revealed nothing.

Deep within the eye lies a vast stretch of dark
sky that rumbles with an endless meteor storm.
The slightest rub of the tiny orb, and the rock
will tumble and soar.

Madara’s Whistle: Whistle of the Madaras twins, denizens of the Forbidden Woods.
The twins grew up alongside a poisonous snake, and
developed a silent, inhuman kinship.

The poisonous snake grew uncontrollably, raised on a
healthy diet of beast entrails. Even after their deaths, it is
said to respond to the call of the twins' whistle from within the Nightmare.


Online Items:
Beckoning Bell: Great Old Bell discovered in the underground labyrinth.

Its ring resonates across worlds, and the first hunter used it
as a special signal to call hunters from other worlds to cross
the gap and cooperate.

A human must use Insight to ring this uncanny bell, but the
benefits of cross-world cooperation are many.

Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.

League Staff: The League staff is the sign of a confederate.
A directory within the hilt lists the names of fellow
confederates.

Members of the League brandish this staff to indicate
themselves to fellow members of the League.

        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 84


There shall be no sympathy for those engaged in the bloody
mission of the League. No matter that an oath must be taken
to uphold the illusion.

Notebook: Messengers are inhabitants of the dream who revere the
brave hunters. Use them to send messages to other worlds.

Leave notes with messengers, read the notes left by
messengers in other worlds, and rate notes to participate
in the formation of a shared inter-plane intelligence.

Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.

Silencing Blank: Hunters are linked by the resonance of bells with special
encoded timbres. This inaudible burst disrupts such
resonance.

Fire to end co-operation, and prevent further co-operation.
Firing this does not disrupt the resonance of a sinister bell.

Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.

Sinister Resonant Bell: A blood-stained bell discovered in the old underground
labyrinth.

One of the resonating bells that cross the gaps of worlds, but
this one knells for misfortune and malice.

The Sinister Bell is an object of dark thoughts. Ring it to
become the enemy of a hunter in another world.

Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.

Small Resonant Bell: Small bell discovered in the old underground labyrinth.

Its ring resonates across worlds, and the first hunter
used it as a special signal to call hunters from other
worlds to cross the gap and cooperate.

This bell resonates with its counterpart, the Beckoning


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                    Script 85


Bell. Ring to help hunters in other worlds.

Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.

Vileblood Register: Red-leather record of the Vilebloods loyal to the covenant of
Annalise, Queen of the Vilebloods, at Cainhurst Castle.

A record of the Vilebloods, blood-lusting hunters who seek
blood dregs of their prey, kept throughout the ages.

Note: Online use only. Cannot use this item offline.


Chalice Ritual Materials:
Arcane Haze: Material used in a Holy Chalice rite.

The tiny smatterings of haze that are found in certain
ritual materials. Sometimes required for special rites.

The additional rite Sinister Bell makes the bell-ringing
woman appear, and when she rings a sinister bell, hunters
from other worlds will be beckoned as adversaries.

Bloodshot Eyeball: Material used in a Holy Chalice rite.

An exquisite eyeball removed quickly after death,
or perhaps even before. Used to unlock the seal
of the old labyrinth hintertombs.

Blooming Coldbood Flower: Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.

Pale vegetation that commonly grows on coldblood in a
place long abandoned, that has bloomed into a bright red
stygian flower.

Coldblood Flowerbud: Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.

Pale vegetation that commonly grows on coldblood in a
place long ago abandoned.


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 86


Coldblood Flower Bulb: Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.

Pale vegetation that commonly grows on coldblood in a
place long abandoned, said to mature slowly in close
proximity to death, and eventually bloom.

Pearl Slug: Material used in a Holy Chalice rite.

Of the all the strange lifeforms that reside in
the nooks and crannies of the old labyrinth,
the slugs are clear signs of the left-behind Great Ones.

Red Jelly: Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.

Stillborn infants born of a creature of unknown origin, of the
type found in some corners of the old labyrinth.

Ritual Blood: Material used in a Holy Chalice rite.

One of the basic ingredients used to satiate a Holy Chalice is this
incoagulable blood.

When all is melted in blood, all is reborn.

Tomb Mold: Material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.

Mould that grows from rotten flesh and blood inside the old
labyrinth. Matures to bear giant spores.

Bastard of Loran: Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.

Remains of Loran infant infected by the scourge.
A harbinger of curses and symbol of defilement.

The additional rite Curse defiles dungeons in which hunters'
HP is greatly eroded, but what better place to seek cursed
blood gems but in the midst of defilement?




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                    Script 87


Inflicted Organ: Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.

Special body parts collected by the Healing Church.
What was this gruesome bait used to lure?

The additional rite Rotted Offering beckons ungodly forces,
normally terrifying things, but also worthy prey for a special
hunt.

Living String: Special material used in a holy chalice ritual.

The immense brain that Mensis retrieved from the nightmare
was indeed lined with eyes on the inside, but they were of
an evil sort, and the brain itself was terrible rotten.

But even still, it was a legitimate Great One, and left a relic.
A living relic, at that, which is a precious thing indeed.

Sage’s Hair: Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.

A body part of a saint, sacrificed by the Healing Church in
their search for Truth.

The additional rite Fetid Offering invigorates the Watchers,
making them more treacherous than normal, but also making
them worthy prey for a special hunt.

Sage’s Wrist: Special material used in a Holy Chalice ritual.

A body part of a saint, sacrificed by the Healing Church in
their search for Truth.

The additional rite Fetid Offering invigorates the Watchers,
making them more treacherous than normal, but also making
them worthy prey for a special hunt.

Yellow Backbone: Special material used in a Holy Chalice rite.

Special body parts collected by the Healing Church.
What was this gruesome bait used to lure?


         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 88


Caryll Runes:
Beast Rune: A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.

A transcription of the roar of a labyrinth beast, the bearer of
the "Beast" rune has accentuated transformation effects.

"Beast" is one of the early Caryll Runes, as well as one of the
first to be deemed forbidden. The discovery of blood entailed
the discovery of undesirable beasts.

Blood Rapture Rune: A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
"Blood Rapture" is the raw euphoria of the warmth of blood.
Restores HP with visceral attacks, one of the darker hunter
techniques.

This rune resonates with servants of the Queen, carrier of
the Child of Blood, who yearn for their Queen's blood with
little hope of requitement.

For them, they find solace in "Blood Rapture," that serves as
a surrogate for their desires.

Clawmark Rune: A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.

The "Clawmark" is an impulse to seek the warmth of blood
like a beast. It strengthens visceral attacks, one of the darker
hunter techniques.

Although the difference is subtle, Runesmith Caryll describes
the "Beast" as a horrific and unwelcome instinct deep within
the hearts of men, while "Clawmark" is an alluring invitation
to accept this very nature.

Communion Rune: A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.

Several runes relate to "blood," including "Communion,"
which raises the maximum number of blood vials
one may carry.


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 89


This rune represents the Healing Church and its
ministers. Blood ministration is, of course, the pursuit
of communion.

Eye Rune: A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.

A transcription of "eye," as spoken by left-behind Great
Ones. Allows one to make additional discoveries.

Eyes symbolize the truth Master Willem sought in his
research. Disillusioned by the limits of human intellect,
Master Willem looked to beings from higher planes for
guidance, and sought to line his brain with eyes in order to
elevate his thoughts.

Formless Oedon Rune: A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.

The Great One Oedon, lacking form, exists only in voice,
and is symbolised by this rune. Those who memorise it enjoy
a larger supply of Quicksilver Bullets.

Human or no, the oozing blood is a medium of the highest
grade, and the essence of the formless Great One, Oedon.
Both Oedon, and his inadvertent worshippers, surreptitiously
seek the precious blood.

Heir Rune: A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.

The "Heir" sees sentimentality in the warmth of blood, and
acknowledges visceral attacks as one of the darker hunter
techniques.

More blood echoes gained from visceral attacks.

Perhaps the "Heir" is a hunter who bears the echoing will of
those before him.

Moon Rune: A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.

A transcription of "moon," as spoken by the Great Ones


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 90


inhabiting the nightmare.

Gain more Blood Echoes.

The Great Ones that inhabit the nightmare are
sympathetic in spirit, and often answer when called upon.

Oedon Writhe Rune: A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.

"Writhe" sees a subtle mucous in the warmth of blood,
and acknowledges visceral attacks as one of the darker hunter
techniques. Visceral attacks restore Quicksilver Bullets.

Human or no. the oozing blood is a medium of the highest
grade, and the essence of the formless Great One, Oedon.
Both Oedon, and Oedon's inadvertent worshippers,
surreptitiously seek the precious blood.

Guidance Rune: A Caryll rune discovered by the old hunter Ludwig along
with the Holy Moonlight Sword.
Boosts amount of life recovered by rallying.

When Ludwig closed his eyes, he saw darkness, or perhaps
nothingness, and that is where he discovered the tiny beings
of light. Ludwig was certain that these playful dancing
sprites offered "guidance," and emptied Ludwig of his fears
at least in the midst of a hunt.

Lake Runes: A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.

This transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices
ripples like a watery reflection. This rune means "Lake,"
and those branded by it enjoy augmented defense.

Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark guarding sleep,
and an augur of the eldritch Truth.

Overcome this hindrance, and seek what is yours.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 91


Anti-Clockwise Metamorphosis rune: A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of
Byrgenwerth.

The twisted cross means "metamorphosis."

Rotated anti-clockwise, this rune boosts stamina.

The discovery of blood made their dream of evolution
a reality, Metamorphosis, and the excesses and deviation
that followed, was only the beginning.

Clockwise Metamorphosis Rune: A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.

The twisted cross means "metamorphosis."

Rotated clockwise, this rune boosts HP.

The discovery of blood made their dream of evolution
a reality. Metamorphosis, and the excesses and deviation
that followed. were only the beginning.

Sea Runes: A Caryll rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.

This transcription of the Great Ones' inhuman voices depicts
downreaching currents. This rune means "Deep Sea," and
grants augmented resistance.

Great volumes of water serve as a bulwark guarding sleep,
and an augur of the eldritch Truth.

Overcome this hindrance, and seek what is yours.

Corruption Rune: A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.

Several runes contain a nuance of "Blood," including the
rune of "Corruption," associated with the oath of the corrupt.

Pledgers to this oath are Cainhurst Vilebloods, hunters of
blood who find dregs for their Queen in coldblood,
particularly in that of hunters.


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 92


Yet the corrupt are heretics in the eyes of the Church, and
thus subject to the wrath of the Executioners.

Hunter Rune: A Caryll Rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.

This red-smudged rune means "Hunter," and has been
adopted by those who have taken the Hunter of Hunters oath.
These watchmen admonish those who have become addled
with blood. Be they men or beasts, anyone who has
threatened the pledgers of the "Hunter" oath surely has an
issue with blood.

Impurity Rune: A Carryl rune that transcribes inhuman sounds.
This rune, discovered inside the forbidden beast eater, came
to symbolize "Impurity," and the oath of the League.

Confederates of The League cooperate with hunters from
other worlds, and hunt to discover vermin.
Vermin writhe within filth, and are the root of man's
impurity. Crush all vermin without hesitation.

Radiance Rune: A secret symbol left by Caryll, runesmith of Byrgenwerth.

The rune for "Radiance," adopted by the sworn
Executioners under Logarius' command.

The executioners despise the impure Vilebloods,
and no matter what the circumstances, would
never cooperate with the bloodthirsty hunters
who serve the undead queen, Annalise.

Beast’s Embrace Rune: After repeated experiments in controlling the scourge of
beasts, the gentle "Embrace" rune was discovered.

When its implementation failed, the "Embrace" became a
forbidden rune, but its knowledge became a foundation of
the Healing Church.

Those who swear this oath take on a ghastly form, and enjoy
accentuated transformation effects, especially while wielding a beast weapon.


        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                   Script 93


Milkweed Rune: A Caryll rune envisioned by Adeline, patient of the
research hall.

A transcription of the inhuman, sticky whispers that reveal
the nature of a celestial attendant.
Those who take this oath become a lumenwood that peers
towards the sky, feeding phantasms in its luscious bed.
Phantasms guide us and lead us to further discoveries.


Holy Chalices:
Pthumeru Chalice: Ritual chalice found in the Church of the Good Chalice.

Use in a ritual at the tomb altar in the Hunter's Dream
to break the seal of the old underground labyrinth.

Let the chalice reveal the tomb of the gods; let blood
be the hunter's nourishment.

...And let ye partake in communion...

Pthumeru Root Chalice: Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.

Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth
seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time.

The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians,
superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked
the wisdom of the eldritch Truth.

Central Pthumeru Chalice: A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal.

But only a Root Chalice changes the shape of the
old labyrinth when used in a ritual.

The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians,
superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked
the wisdom of the eldritch Truth.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                     Script 94


Central Pthumeru Root Chalice: Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.

Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth
seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time.

The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians,
superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked
the wisdom of the eldritch Truth.

Lower Pthumeru Chalice: A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal.

But only a Root Chalice changes the shape of the
old labyrinth when used in a ritual.

The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians,
superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked
the wisdom of the eldritch Truth.

Lower Pthumeru Root Chalice: Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.

Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth
seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time.

The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians,
superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked
the wisdom of the eldritch Truth.

Sinister Lower Pthumeru Root Chalice: Root chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.

When used in a ritual, this sinister chalice summons the
Sinister Resonant Bell. The bell-ringing woman appears to be
a mad Pthumerian.
The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians,
superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked the
wisdom of the eldritch Truth.

Note: Additional rite Sinister Bell is for online use only.
The bell-ringing woman does not appear offline.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                      Script 95


Defiled Chalice: A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal.

Only, this defiled chalice is cursed.

Curses are caused by inciting the anger of the Great Ones,
and used to hex others. Special materials are required to
complete the ritual.
To try one's hand at curses, first seek the Bastard of Loran.

Cursed and Defiled Root Chalice: Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.

This cursed chalice makes a special ritual possible, but must
not be used lightly, as the resulting transformation can be
utterly drastic.

The old labyrinth was carved out by the Pthumerians,
superhuman beings that are said to have unlocked the
wisdom of the eldritch Truth.

Great Pthumeru Ihyll Chalice: A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal.

Great chalices unlock deeper reaches of the labyrinth.
Pthumeru Ihyll was the title of both the
Pthumerian monarch and its capital.

This reveals that while early Pthumerians were mere
humble guardians of the slumbering Great Ones, their
descendants felt entitled to name themselves a leader.

Pthumeru Ihyll Root Chalice: Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.

Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth
seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time.

The Pthumerian monarch was traditionally a woman
who assumed a name with classical roots.




        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                      Script 96


Sinister Pthumeru Ihyll Root Chalice: Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.
When used in a ritual, this sinister chalice summons

the Sinister Resonant Bell. The bell-ringing woman appears to be a mad Pthumerian.

The Pthumerian monarch was traditionally a woman
who assumed a name with classical roots.

Note: Additional rite Sinister Bell is for online use only.
the bell-ringing woman does not appear offline.

Hintertomb Chalice: A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal.
Hintertombs are the peripheral catacombs
of the old underground labyrinth.

To this day, the Watcher continue to expand the
hintertombs, unceremonious catacombs filled with
graves and death.

Hintertomb Root Chalice: Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.

Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth
seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time.

The hintertombs are unceremonious homes to graves
and death, cesspools of noxious snakes and insects.

Lower Hintertomb Chalice: A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal.
Hintertombs are the peripheral catacombs
of the old underground labyrinth.

To this day, the Watchers continue to expand the
hintertombs, unceremonious catacombs filled with
graves and death.

Lower Hintertomb Root Chalice: Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.

Root Chalices, used in rituals to break old labyrinth
seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time.



        ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                       Script 97


The hintertombs are unceremonious homes to graves
and death, cesspools of noxious snakes and insects.

Sinister Hintertomb Root Chalice: Root chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.
When used in a ritual, this sinister chalice summons the
Sinister Resonant Bell. The bell-ringing woman appears to be
a mad Pthumerian.

The hintertombs are unceremonious homes to graves and
death, cesspools of noxious snakes and insects.

Note: Additional rite Sinister Bell is for online use only.
The bell-ringing woman does not appear offline.

Ailing Loran Chalice: A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal.
Loran is a tragic land that was devoured by the sands.

The tragedy that struck this ailing land of Loran
is said to have its roots in the scourge of the beast.

Some have made the dreaded extrapolation that
Yharnam may be next.

Ailing Loran Root Chalice: Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.

Root Chalices, used in rituals to break labyrinth
seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time.

There are trace remains of medical procedures in
parts of ailing Loran. Whether these were attempts to
control the scourge of the beast, or the cause of the
outbreak, is unknown.

Lower Ailing Loran Chalice: A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal.
But only a Root Chalice changes the shape of the
Chalice Dungeon when used in a ritual.

There are trace remains of medical procedures in
parts of ailing Loran. Whether these were attempts to
control the scourge of the beast, or the cause of the outbreak, is unknown.


         ________________________________________________________________________
                                                                                       Script 98


Sinister Lower Loran Chalice: Root chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.

When used in a ritual, this sinister chalice summons the
Sinister Resonant Bell. The bell-ringing woman appears to be
a mad Pthumerian.

There are trace remains of medical procedures in parts of
ailing Loran. Whether these were attempts to control the
scourge of the beast, or the cause of the
outbreak, is unknown.

Note: Additional rite Sinister Bell is for online use only.
The bell-ringing woman does not appear offline.

Great Isz Chalice: A chalice that breaks a labyrinth seal.

Great chalices unlock deeper reaches of the labyrinth. The
Great Isz Chalice became the cornerstone of the Choir, the
elite delegation of the Healing Church.

It was also the first Great Chalice brought back to the
surface since the time of Byrgenwerth, and allowed the
Choir to have audience with Ebrietas.

Isz Root Chalice: Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.

Root Chalices, used in rituals to break labyrinth
seals, are said to change the labyrinth's form each time.

According to the Choir, the land of Izs lies in contact
with the cosmos, which allowed the Great Ones to
function on transcendental planes of thought.

Sinister Isz Root Chalice: Root Chalice that breaks multiple labyrinth seals.

When used in a ritual, this sinister chalice summons the
Sinister Resonant Bell. The bell-ringing woman appears to be
a mad Pthumerian.
According to the Choir, the land of Izs lies in contact
with the cosmos, which allowed the Great Ones to function on transcendental planes of thought.

</root>